<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Nikolai Nekrutenko</title>
        <link>/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Nikolai Nekrutenko</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 10:30:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>EOLRC - Build Guide</title>
            <link>/posts/eolrc-build-guide/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 10:30:15 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/eolrc-build-guide/</guid>
            <description>Note that this is not a build guide of the car itself. Rather, how to integrate the 3D printed parts with the plane parts for your own projects.
Printing the parts The parts can be found in the plans GitHub repo.
I recommend printing the All_parts_arranged.stl
I used an Ultimaker 3 to print the parts with eSun PLA+ at a 0.2mm layer height at 215C, 35% infill, along with a PETG brim for easy cleanup.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Note that this is not a build guide of the car itself. Rather, how to integrate the 3D printed parts with the plane parts for your own projects.</p>
<h1 id="printing-the-parts">Printing the parts</h1>
<p><strong>The parts can be found in the <a href="https://github.com/NikolaiTeslovich/plans/tree/master/EOLRC">plans GitHub repo</a>.</strong></p>
<p>I recommend printing the All_parts_arranged.stl</p>
<p>I used an Ultimaker 3 to print the parts with eSun PLA+ at a 0.2mm layer height at 215C, 35% infill, along with a PETG brim for easy cleanup. They were printed relatively slow at 60mm/s.</p>
<p>The print took about an hour and a half and used under 20 grams of filament.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC1.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>3D printed parts fresh off the printer</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h1 id="bill-of-parts">Bill of parts</h1>
<ul>
<li><strong>Part (what I used)</strong></li>
<li>Battery (3S1P 2200mAh LiPo)</li>
<li>Electronic speed controller (BLHeli 20A brushless)</li>
<li>Motor with a 16mm by 19mm mounting screw arrangement (Flite Test Radial 2212-1050kV)</li>
<li>Radio receiver (FrSky X4R)</li>
<li>9g servo (some cheap one off Amazon)</li>
<li>All in one FPV camera (AKK 40CH 5.8G 0/25/50/200mW Switchable Micro AIO FPV Camera)</li>
<li>3D printed parts</li>
<li>Screws (All of these come with the servo and motor)
<ul>
<li>4x cone-shaped motor screws</li>
<li>2x long servo screws</li>
<li>1x short servo screw</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC2.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>Parts laid out</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h1 id="bill-of-tools">Bill of tools</h1>
<ul>
<li>Adjustable wrench</li>
<li>Phillips No. 1 screwdriver</li>
<li>Radio control transmitter/remote</li>
<li>FPV goggles with a 5.8GHz system</li>
</ul>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC3.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>Tools laid out</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h1 id="lets-put-the-parts-together-damn-it">Let&rsquo;s put the parts together damn it!</h1>
<h2 id="step-1---binding-the-receiver">Step 1 - Binding the receiver</h2>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC4.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>Sample binding circuit</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Make a new model with zero trims. Check with your manufacturer&rsquo;s instructions on binding the radio with the receiver.</p>
<p>We&rsquo;ll need this for a later step.</p>
<h2 id="step-2---attaching-the-motor-to-axle-adapter-to-the-motor">Step 2 - Attaching the motor to axle adapter to the motor</h2>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC5.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h3 id="partstools">Parts/Tools</h3>
<ul>
<li>Motor with a 16mm by 19mm mounting arrangement</li>
<li>Motor to axle adapter</li>
<li>Adjustable wrench</li>
</ul>
<p>You can use additional tools for this, but be careful to <em><strong>not</strong></em> <strong>misshape the motor bell</strong>. I totally haven&rsquo;t done that before.</p>
<h3 id="steps">Steps</h3>
<ol>
<li>Screw on the motor to axle adapter onto the motor while making sure that it is screwed all the way down.</li>
</ol>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC6.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h2 id="step-3---affixing-the-motor-to-the-motor-mount">Step 3 - Affixing the motor to the motor mount</h2>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC7.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h3 id="partstools-1">Parts/Tools</h3>
<ul>
<li>Motor from step 2</li>
<li>Motor mount</li>
<li>4x cone-shaped motor screws</li>
<li>Philips No. 1 screwdriver</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="steps-1">Steps</h3>
<ol>
<li>Attach the motor to the motor mount using the screws</li>
</ol>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC8.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h2 id="step-4---mounting-the-servo-to-the-servo-holder">Step 4 - Mounting the servo to the servo holder</h2>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC9.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h3 id="partstools-2">Parts/Tools</h3>
<ul>
<li>9g servo</li>
<li>Servo mount</li>
<li>2x long servo screws</li>
<li>Philips No. 1 screwdriver</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="steps-2">Steps</h3>
<ol>
<li>Push the servo into the mount until it is flush</li>
<li>Screw in the screws to secure the Servo</li>
</ol>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC10.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h2 id="step-5---securing-the-servo-arm-to-the-servo">Step 5 - Securing the servo arm to the servo</h2>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC11.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h3 id="partstools-3">Parts/Tools</h3>
<ul>
<li>Radio receiver</li>
<li>Battery</li>
<li>Electronic speed controller</li>
<li>Servo assembly from step 4</li>
<li>Servo arm</li>
<li>1x short servo screw</li>
<li>Philips No. 1 screwdriver</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="steps-3">Steps</h3>
<ol>
<li>Plug the battery into the electronic speed controller</li>
<li>Power on the radio receiver using the electronic speed controller</li>
<li>Plug the servo wire into the second channel of the speed controller</li>
<li>Turn on the radio controller, it should connect to the radio receiver</li>
<li>Test that the servo works by moving the sticks on the controller</li>
<li>While leaving the sticks of the radio centered, line up the servo arm parallel to the long side of the servo mount and screw it in. (This is so that the servo arm is centered)</li>
</ol>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC12.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h2 id="step-6---fixing-the-aio-fpv-camera-to-the-camera-mount">Step 6 - Fixing the AIO FPV camera to the camera mount</h2>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC13.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h3 id="partstools-4">Parts/Tools</h3>
<ul>
<li>AIO FPV camera</li>
<li>Camera mount</li>
<li>Hot glue (optional)</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="steps-4">Steps</h3>
<ol>
<li>(Optional) Put hot glue inside the camera mount. This will secure the camera much more than just pushing it in and having it stay attached due to friction.</li>
<li>Carefully yet forcefully push the camera into the Camera mount. The camera lens should be flush with the exterior of the mount.</li>
</ol>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC14.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h1 id="making-sure-that-the-whole-system-works">Making sure that the whole system works</h1>
<p>These gifs were recorded through the FPV camera, so at least I know that that works.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/controller.gif"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>Moving the controller&#39;s sticks</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>With everything properly wired up, it was time to test all the parts.</p>
<ul>
<li>The three motor cables were joined with the ones coming out of the electronic speed controller (ESC)</li>
<li>The ESC cable was plugged into the first channel of the receiver</li>
<li>The FPV camera was plugged into 5V BEC output of the ESC, for which I made a custom splitter</li>
<li>The servo cable was plugged into the second channel of the receiver</li>
<li>Obviously the battery was plugged into the ESC</li>
</ul>
<p>When I moved the left stick of the controller vertically, the motor span up. When I moved the right stick on the controller horizontally, the servo turned.</p>
<p><strong>If you want to reverse the motor direction, just swap any two of the three motor wires</strong></p>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/servomotor.gif"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>Servo and motor responding to my inputs</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h1 id="what-next">What next?</h1>
<p><strong>Congratulations, you&rsquo;re finally done. Now give yourself a big pat on the back</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Let your imagination run wild! As they say: the sky is the limit!</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="/posts/eolrc-an-extremely-overkill-lego-rc-car-from-plane-parts/">Here&rsquo;s what I built using these parts.</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>EOLRC - An Extremely Overkill LEGO RC Car (from Plane Parts)</title>
            <link>/posts/eolrc-an-extremely-overkill-lego-rc-car-from-plane-parts/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 07:27:42 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/eolrc-an-extremely-overkill-lego-rc-car-from-plane-parts/</guid>
            <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last played around with LEGO Technic. About 4 years to be exact. I can say with absolute confidence that this was my favorite way to spend time in my younger years.
I recollect building all sorts of crazy things from an automatic crossbow to a massive Mercedes Benz Unimog with a functioning suspension and a pneumatic crane. Over the years, I have acquired an impressive amount of LEGO technic parts that are still scattered everywhere around the house.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VaGnldsxeiA?autoplay=1" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h2 id="its-been-a-while">It&rsquo;s been a while</h2>
<p>since I last played around with LEGO Technic. About 4 years to be exact. I can say with absolute confidence that this was my favorite way to spend time in my
younger years.</p>
<p>I recollect building all sorts of crazy things from an automatic crossbow to a massive Mercedes Benz Unimog with a functioning suspension and a pneumatic crane. Over the years, I have acquired an impressive amount of LEGO technic parts that are still scattered everywhere around the house.</p>
<h2 id="i-recently-had-to-decommission">I recently had to decommission</h2>
<p>one of my favorite birds of all time. It was a <a href="https://www.flitetest.com/articles/ft-versa-wing">FT(Flite Test) Versa wing</a> with the <a href="https://www.flitetest.com/articles/blunt-nose-conversion-ft-versa-build">Blunt Nose modification</a>. It had to be put out of service due to a combination of old age and abuse like trying to hit a small gap between the trees.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/versa1.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>FT Blunt Nose Versa</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>This gave me several spare electronic components including a 20A BLHeli brushless ESC(electronic speed controller), a radio receiver, a Flite Test Radial 2212-1050kV motor, and an AIO(all in one) FPV camera.</p>
<h2 id="i-hopped-onto-fusion-360">I hopped onto Fusion 360</h2>
<p>and started modeling adapters to those electronic components so that they could be compatible with LEGO Technic. I&rsquo;ll be honest, it took multiple iterations to design parts that interfaced well with the plane and LEGO parts.</p>
<p>In the end, I designed and printed four parts: a servo holder so that the RC car could steer, a motor to lego axle adapter, a FPV camera holder, and last but not least a motor mount. Later on, I also designed an arm from the servo to the lego steering mechanism, but this is not in the pictures shown below.</p>
<p><strong>A build guide will also be written soon, so stay posted.</strong> <em><strong>Update</strong></em> <a href="/posts/eolrc-build-guide/">It&rsquo;s already written.</a></p>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/rclego1.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>3D printed parts</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure>
    <img src="/img/rclego2.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>3D printed parts with the electronics in them</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="here-is-the-final-result">Here is the final result:</h2>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/rclego3.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>The RC car in all its might</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure>
    <img src="/img/rclego4.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>The RC car at night</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="i-have-to-say">I have to say</h2>
<p>I am very impressed with the performance of this car. It has enough torque to just about climb over anything and on a 3S 2200mAh LiPo, the battery lasts for ages, about 1.5 hrs of regular use.</p>
<p>However, LEGO Technic clearly isn&rsquo;t designed for this. For instance, the lego axles heated up so much that they fused the gears onto them permanently. I sprayed the moving parts with WD-40, but that didn&rsquo;t seem to help too much.</p>
<p>I also did some water testing, and it seems to be surprisingly waterproof. <strong>Please don&rsquo;t abuse your electronics.</strong> I did it so that you wouldn&rsquo;t have to.</p>
<h2 id="what-are-its-features">What are its features?</h2>
<ul>
<li>A fully functioning differential</li>
<li>Optional 5mm led lights</li>
<li>FPV</li>
<li>Hella battery life</li>
<li>Quick and easy to build and repair after a crash</li>
<li>Customizability that comes with LEGO</li>
<li>Probably cheaper than buying the LEGO electronics</li>
<li>Extremely overpowered</li>
<li>Surprisingly waterproof</li>
<li>Extremely unstable</li>
<li>Brings back childhood nostalgia</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Let&#39;s Kill This MacBook! - How to Mine Monero on a Mac</title>
            <link>/posts/lets-kill-this-macbook-how-to-mine-monero-on-a-mac/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 10:04:55 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/lets-kill-this-macbook-how-to-mine-monero-on-a-mac/</guid>
            <description>MacBook Pro 13 without TouchBar   My good friend&amp;rsquo;s Mac is nearing its end He&amp;rsquo;s already had it, the one in the picture above, for a couple of years, and the battery is starting to degrade among several other serious issues. Since it is nearing its end soon, in the time that it isn&amp;rsquo;t being used it could mine some cryptocurrency.
MacBooks are known for their subpar cooling systems as demonstrated in this video.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<figure>
    <img src="/img/skylerdontlikemacs.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>MacBook Pro 13 without TouchBar</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h1 id="my-good-friends-mac-is-nearing-its-end">My good friend&rsquo;s Mac is nearing its end</h1>
<p>He&rsquo;s already had it, the one in the picture above, for a couple of years, and the battery is starting to degrade among several other serious issues. Since it is nearing its end soon, in the time that it isn&rsquo;t being used it could mine some cryptocurrency.</p>
<p>MacBooks are known for their subpar cooling systems as demonstrated in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MlOPPuNv4Ec">this video</a>. We are going to set up this mac for mining <a href="https://www.getmonero.org/">Monero(XMR)</a>, a type of cryptocurrency that can be mined with a CPU. He is only going to earn a couple pennies per day, but it&rsquo;s better than nothing. I don&rsquo;t know how he&rsquo;ll be able to sleep through the insane fan noise. Maybe he&rsquo;ll have to run an extension cable to his closet.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/monero.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>Official Monero Logo</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h1 id="disclaimer">Disclaimer</h1>
<p>You have been warned that there are risks such as damage to the computer keeping it at a high temperature for long periods of time.</p>
<p>It is barely profitable to do this on a laptop.</p>
<p>Pools usually have a minimum of 0.1 XMR payout, so it would take at least a couple of months to be able to withdraw the Monero if using a laptop.</p>
<p>Please do this at your own risk.</p>
<h1 id="installing-xmrig">Installing xmrig</h1>
<p><em><strong>Open the terminal application on your mac and copy and paste the code below into it, step by step.</strong></em></p>
<p>Install Homebrew, a package manager for macOS:</p>
<p><code>/bin/bash -c &quot;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/install.sh)&quot;</code></p>
<p>Install the required dependencies with Homebrew:</p>
<p><code>brew install git cmake libuv libmicrohttpd openssl hwloc</code></p>
<p>Clone, or in other words, save the xmrig mining software to your computer with git:</p>
<p><code>git clone https://github.com/xmrig/xmrig.git</code></p>
<p>Make the build directory inside of the xmrig directory:</p>
<p><code>mkdir xmrig/build</code></p>
<p>Navigate into the build directory inside xmrig:</p>
<p><code>cd xmrig/build</code></p>
<p>Build the program with cmake, then make:</p>
<p><code>cmake .. -DOPENSSL_ROOT_DIR=/usr/local/opt/openssl</code></p>
<p><code>make -j$(sysctl -n hw.logicalcpu)</code></p>
<h1 id="generating-the-xmrig-config-code">Generating the xmrig config code</h1>
<p>The people over at xmrig made a fantastic configuration wizard which helps create a line of code to start the miner.</p>
<p>Open the <a href="https://xmrig.com/wizard">xmrig configuration wizard</a></p>
<p>Click the <strong>New configuration</strong> button.</p>
<p>Press on the <strong>Add pool</strong> button.</p>
<p>Click on your pool of choice in the dropdown. I use the supporxmr.com pool.</p>
<p>Then there will be a pop-up where it asks for the <strong>Monero wallet address</strong>, where you type in your wallet. You can also choose to set a <strong>Worker name</strong>, something like MacBookPro13.</p>
<p>Navigate to the <strong>Backends</strong> tab and only turn on the <strong>CPU</strong> option. You can use a GPU if you have one, but I don&rsquo;t recommend it as there are far more profitable currencies to mine with a GPU.</p>
<p>Next, select the <strong>Misc</strong> tab and set a donation percentage, I chose to leave the <strong>HTTP API</strong> option off.</p>
<p>Finally, navigate the the <strong>Result</strong> tab, click on macOS option under the <strong>Command line</strong>. Copy the line of code.</p>
<h1 id="making-an-executable-shell-script">Making an executable shell script</h1>
<p>While this is not a required step, I recommend that you do it for ease of use.</p>
<p>Go back to the terminal app.</p>
<p>If it is still open, navigate to the user(<strong>~</strong>) directory:</p>
<p><code>cd .. &amp;&amp; cd ..</code></p>
<p>If you reopened it, double check that you are in the <strong>~</strong> directory.</p>
<p>Create a shell script called xmr:</p>
<p><code>touch xmr.sh</code></p>
<p>Make it executable:</p>
<p><code>chmod +x xmr.sh</code></p>
<p>Edit the shell script to make it navigate to the xmrig/build directory, and start the miner from there:</p>
<p><code>nano xmr.sh</code></p>
<p>A basic text editor will show up.</p>
<p>Type the following into it, each on a separate line:</p>
<p><code>cd xmrig/build</code></p>
<p><code>copy and paste the code that we generated earlier from the configurator</code></p>
<p>Press control x, press y to apply the changes, and then press enter to save the edits made to the file.</p>
<h1 id="running-the-shell-script">Running the shell script</h1>
<p>It&rsquo;s actually really easy, type the following into terminal from the <strong>~</strong> directory, which is the default when you open Terminal:</p>
<p><code>./xmr.sh</code></p>
<p>To stop the program press control c.</p>
<p>You can monitor all sorts of statistics on the pool&rsquo;s home page, logging in with your wallet address as your username.</p>
<h1 id="updating-xmrig">Updating xmrig</h1>
<p>Navigate to the build directory:</p>
<p><code>cd xmrig/build</code></p>
<p>Update using the git pull command:</p>
<p><code>git pull</code></p>
<h1 id="resources">Resources</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Based around the <a href="https://xmrig.com/docs/miner/macos-build">official xmrig macOS build guide</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://coin360.com/coin/monero-xmr">Monero(XMR) price chart</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.getmonero.org/">Monero&rsquo;s official website</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My First Post</title>
            <link>/posts/my-first-post/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 15:21:48 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
            <description>Hello World!
Why did I make this website and what even is it? I&amp;rsquo;m glad you asked although you probably didn&amp;rsquo;t! I made and will continue to make this website because I want to learn how to build a website. I also enjoy writing, especially when it isn&amp;rsquo;t tied to a grade.
I will be posting about everything from a small cryptocurrency mining operation that I run in the basement to my favorite hobby of RC flight to my own ice cream recipes and everything in between.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello World!</p>
<h2 id="why-did-i-make-this-website-and-what-even-is-it">Why did I make this website and what even is it?</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;m glad you asked although you probably didn&rsquo;t! I made and <strong>will continue</strong> to make this website because I want to learn how to build a website. I also enjoy writing, especially when it isn&rsquo;t tied to a grade.</p>
<p>I will be posting about everything from a small cryptocurrency mining operation that I run in the basement to my favorite hobby of RC flight to my own ice cream recipes and everything in between. In short, the things that I do to keep myself sane, especially during quarantine. I&rsquo;ll post at least every week. This is my blog site.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
