<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Nikolai Nekrutenko</title>
        <link>/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Nikolai Nekrutenko</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 15:12:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>The Mostly Maine Trip Video</title>
            <link>/posts/the-mostly-maine-trip-video/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 15:12:36 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/the-mostly-maine-trip-video/</guid>
            <description>Enjoy this video, I&amp;rsquo;m really proud of how it turned out!
  I finally convinced my best friend to lend me his drone after days of trying.
I actually have a drone, an EMAX Tinyhawk 2, which note to self I still need to fix. I crashed it pretty hard flying on the porch of my house against a metal support beam and one of the ESC&amp;rsquo;s is burned out.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enjoy this video, I&rsquo;m really proud of how it turned out!</strong></p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RvZXMa7au5k?autoplay=1" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p>I finally convinced my best friend to lend me his drone after days of trying.</p>
<p>I actually have a drone, an EMAX Tinyhawk 2, which <strong>note to self</strong> I still need to fix. I crashed it pretty hard flying on the porch of my house against a metal support beam and one of the ESC&rsquo;s is burned out.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/tinyhawkII.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>EMAX Tinyhawk II with the Luminier AXII modification</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Enough about my drone. My friend lent me a DJI Mavic Air which is very different from my drone. My drone is meant for flying around and exploring. Crashing it is okay, and it doesn&rsquo;t record any video. The DJI Mavic Air, on the other hand, can record beautiful video at 4k 30fps. It&rsquo;s much larger and can fly for much longer, 15 mins vs 3 mins for my drone.</p>
<p>I just came back from a <a href="/gallery/maine-trip/">trip exploring New England</a>, and captured some astonishing footage with his drone. The DJI Mavic air is pictured in the thumbnail of this video.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>New Instagram Account</title>
            <link>/posts/new-instagram-account/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 11:58:50 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/new-instagram-account/</guid>
            <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve posted anything on social media, with YouTube being the only exception. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even go as far as to call it social media. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s almost been three years since I posted anything on my personal instagram account @nikolaiteslovich.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I stopped. I guess it just happened.
These times are now gone, with the commencement of a new Instagram account: @projectniknek which you should totally follow by the way.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been a while since I&rsquo;ve posted anything on social media, with YouTube being the only exception. I wouldn&rsquo;t even go as far as to call it social media. In fact, it&rsquo;s almost been three years since I posted anything on my personal instagram account <a href="https://www.instagram.com/nikolaiteslovich/">@nikolaiteslovich</a>.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t know why I stopped. I guess it just happened.</p>
<p>These times are now gone, with the commencement of a new Instagram account: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/projectniknek/">@projectniknek</a> which you should totally follow by the way. I created this to show the world what I&rsquo;m doing with my time: hobbies and projects.</p>


<blockquote class="instagram-media" data-instgrm-captioned data-instgrm-permalink="https://www.instagram.com/p/CEUkxPdHmf6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" data-instgrm-version="12" style=" background:#FFF; border:0; border-radius:3px; box-shadow:0 0 1px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.5),0 1px 10px 0 rgba(0,0,0,0.15); margin: 1px; max-width:658px; min-width:326px; padding:0; width:99.375%; width:-webkit-calc(100% - 2px); width:calc(100% - 2px);"><div style="padding:16px;"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CEUkxPdHmf6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" background:#FFFFFF; line-height:0; padding:0 0; text-align:center; text-decoration:none; width:100%;" target="_blank"> <div style=" display: flex; flex-direction: row; align-items: center;"> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 40px; margin-right: 14px; width: 40px;"></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: column; flex-grow: 1; justify-content: center;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; margin-bottom: 6px; width: 100px;"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 4px; flex-grow: 0; height: 14px; width: 60px;"></div></div></div><div style="padding: 19% 0;"></div> <div style="display:block; height:50px; margin:0 auto 12px; width:50px;"><svg width="50px" height="50px" viewBox="0 0 60 60" version="1.1" xmlns="https://www.w3.org/2000/svg" xmlns:xlink="https://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"><g stroke="none" stroke-width="1" fill="none" fill-rule="evenodd"><g transform="translate(-511.000000, -20.000000)" fill="#000000"><g><path d="M556.869,30.41 C554.814,30.41 553.148,32.076 553.148,34.131 C553.148,36.186 554.814,37.852 556.869,37.852 C558.924,37.852 560.59,36.186 560.59,34.131 C560.59,32.076 558.924,30.41 556.869,30.41 M541,60.657 C535.114,60.657 530.342,55.887 530.342,50 C530.342,44.114 535.114,39.342 541,39.342 C546.887,39.342 551.658,44.114 551.658,50 C551.658,55.887 546.887,60.657 541,60.657 M541,33.886 C532.1,33.886 524.886,41.1 524.886,50 C524.886,58.899 532.1,66.113 541,66.113 C549.9,66.113 557.115,58.899 557.115,50 C557.115,41.1 549.9,33.886 541,33.886 M565.378,62.101 C565.244,65.022 564.756,66.606 564.346,67.663 C563.803,69.06 563.154,70.057 562.106,71.106 C561.058,72.155 560.06,72.803 558.662,73.347 C557.607,73.757 556.021,74.244 553.102,74.378 C549.944,74.521 548.997,74.552 541,74.552 C533.003,74.552 532.056,74.521 528.898,74.378 C525.979,74.244 524.393,73.757 523.338,73.347 C521.94,72.803 520.942,72.155 519.894,71.106 C518.846,70.057 518.197,69.06 517.654,67.663 C517.244,66.606 516.755,65.022 516.623,62.101 C516.479,58.943 516.448,57.996 516.448,50 C516.448,42.003 516.479,41.056 516.623,37.899 C516.755,34.978 517.244,33.391 517.654,32.338 C518.197,30.938 518.846,29.942 519.894,28.894 C520.942,27.846 521.94,27.196 523.338,26.654 C524.393,26.244 525.979,25.756 528.898,25.623 C532.057,25.479 533.004,25.448 541,25.448 C548.997,25.448 549.943,25.479 553.102,25.623 C556.021,25.756 557.607,26.244 558.662,26.654 C560.06,27.196 561.058,27.846 562.106,28.894 C563.154,29.942 563.803,30.938 564.346,32.338 C564.756,33.391 565.244,34.978 565.378,37.899 C565.522,41.056 565.552,42.003 565.552,50 C565.552,57.996 565.522,58.943 565.378,62.101 M570.82,37.631 C570.674,34.438 570.167,32.258 569.425,30.349 C568.659,28.377 567.633,26.702 565.965,25.035 C564.297,23.368 562.623,22.342 560.652,21.575 C558.743,20.834 556.562,20.326 553.369,20.18 C550.169,20.033 549.148,20 541,20 C532.853,20 531.831,20.033 528.631,20.18 C525.438,20.326 523.257,20.834 521.349,21.575 C519.376,22.342 517.703,23.368 516.035,25.035 C514.368,26.702 513.342,28.377 512.574,30.349 C511.834,32.258 511.326,34.438 511.181,37.631 C511.035,40.831 511,41.851 511,50 C511,58.147 511.035,59.17 511.181,62.369 C511.326,65.562 511.834,67.743 512.574,69.651 C513.342,71.625 514.368,73.296 516.035,74.965 C517.703,76.634 519.376,77.658 521.349,78.425 C523.257,79.167 525.438,79.673 528.631,79.82 C531.831,79.965 532.853,80.001 541,80.001 C549.148,80.001 550.169,79.965 553.369,79.82 C556.562,79.673 558.743,79.167 560.652,78.425 C562.623,77.658 564.297,76.634 565.965,74.965 C567.633,73.296 568.659,71.625 569.425,69.651 C570.167,67.743 570.674,65.562 570.82,62.369 C570.966,59.17 571,58.147 571,50 C571,41.851 570.966,40.831 570.82,37.631"></path></g></g></g></svg></div><div style="padding-top: 8px;"> <div style=" color:#3897f0; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:550; line-height:18px;"> View this post on Instagram</div></div><div style="padding: 12.5% 0;"></div> <div style="display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-bottom: 14px; align-items: center;"><div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(0px) translateY(7px);"></div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; height: 12.5px; transform: rotate(-45deg) translateX(3px) translateY(1px); width: 12.5px; flex-grow: 0; margin-right: 14px; margin-left: 2px;"></div> <div style="background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; height: 12.5px; width: 12.5px; transform: translateX(9px) translateY(-18px);"></div></div><div style="margin-left: 8px;"> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; border-radius: 50%; flex-grow: 0; height: 20px; width: 20px;"></div> <div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 2px solid transparent; border-left: 6px solid #f4f4f4; border-bottom: 2px solid transparent; transform: translateX(16px) translateY(-4px) rotate(30deg)"></div></div><div style="margin-left: auto;"> <div style=" width: 0px; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-right: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(16px);"></div> <div style=" background-color: #F4F4F4; flex-grow: 0; height: 12px; width: 16px; transform: translateY(-4px);"></div> <div style=" width: 0; height: 0; border-top: 8px solid #F4F4F4; border-left: 8px solid transparent; transform: translateY(-4px) translateX(8px);"></div></div></div></a> <p style=" margin:8px 0 0 0; padding:0 4px;"> <a href="https://www.instagram.com/p/CEUkxPdHmf6/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#000; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px; text-decoration:none; word-wrap:break-word;" target="_blank">Short edit of a vid I made about a trip I  recently went on. I&#39;m really proud of how it turned out: https://youtu.be/RvZXMa7au5k Filmed on the DJI Mavic Air. Thanks to a friend of mine for letting me use his drone.  #dji #djimavicair #dronecinematography #cinematography #edit #swansisland #maine #summervacation #nofilter #drone #birdseye #aerial #aerialcinematography #ferry #quadcopter #rcdrone #aeronautics #pandemicvacation #covidisass</a></p> <p style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px; margin-bottom:0; margin-top:8px; overflow:hidden; padding:8px 0 7px; text-align:center; text-overflow:ellipsis; white-space:nowrap;">A post shared by <a href="https://www.instagram.com/projectniknek/?utm_source=ig_embed&amp;utm_campaign=loading" style=" color:#c9c8cd; font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; font-style:normal; font-weight:normal; line-height:17px;" target="_blank"> Nikolai Nekrutenko</a> (@projectniknek) on <time style=" font-family:Arial,sans-serif; font-size:14px; line-height:17px;" datetime="2020-08-25T17:57:33+00:00">Aug 25, 2020 at 10:57am PDT</time></p></div></blockquote>
<script async src="//www.instagram.com/embed.js"></script>
<p><strong>In my opinion, especially with the global pandemic that is going on, everyone is becoming more and more connected through the internet.</strong> It&rsquo;s becoming increasingly important, in my view, to become savvy on these social media platforms. It really doesn&rsquo;t take up any extra time, and I enjoy having my friends, and people who share my interests see what neat things I am doing with my time.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Book of Bitcoin - An Analogy to Explain Bitcoin</title>
            <link>/posts/the-book-of-bitcoin-an-analogy-to-explain-bitcoin/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 15:57:01 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/the-book-of-bitcoin-an-analogy-to-explain-bitcoin/</guid>
            <description>This was a project for my speech and debate class, the sources are in the video&amp;rsquo;s description.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the video version of the speech:
  Here&amp;rsquo;s the transcript of the speech:
What do you think of when you hear the word “Bitcoin”? According to a 2017 YouGov survey, 62% of Americans believe that cryptocurrencies, like Bitcoin, are used for illegal purchases or don’t know what they’re used for at all.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a project for my speech and debate class, the sources are in the video&rsquo;s description.</p>
<p><strong>Here&rsquo;s the video version of the speech:</strong></p>

<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IN7gkAQoszo" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<p><strong>Here&rsquo;s the transcript of the speech:</strong></p>
<h1 id="what-do-you-think-of-when-you-hear-the-word-bitcoin">What do you think of when you hear the word “Bitcoin”?</h1>
<p>According to a 2017 YouGov survey, 62% of Americans believe that cryptocurrencies, like Bitcoin, are used for illegal purchases or don’t know what they’re used for at all.
Yet, all the cryptocurrencies combined are estimated to be worth about $230 billion. How much is that exactly? With that amount of money, the US Navy could buy about 20 of the latest Gerald R. Ford-class aircraft carriers.
$230 billion is about the whole GDP of Portugal. I have been interested in Cryptocurrencies ever since I started mining them with my computer at the start of this year.
Only recently, however, did I start to take them seriously through the preparation of this speech.
My name is Nikolai Nekrutenko and today I will attempt to explain what Bitcoin is along with the promise that it and other cryptocurrencies hold for the world’s future.</p>
<h1 id="where-did-money-even-come-from">Where did money even come from?</h1>
<p>According to the book Sapiens by Yuval Noah Hararri, at the very beginning, there was no need for money. Hunters and gatherers shared goods and services through an economy of favors and obligations. For example, if you received a piece of meat from someone and you were known to be good at doctoring, they would expect free medical care.</p>
<p>With the rise of Kingdoms and Empires, the economy based around favors and obligations didn’t work when trying to trade between large numbers of strangers. Since they were strangers, how could they trust each other? What if they didn’t want the services or goods that you were offering? This is where the concept of money came in.</p>
<p>Although we think of it as coins and banknotes, money is simply anything that people are willing to use to represent the value of other things for exchanging goods and services. Everyone always wants money because everyone else also wants money. We accept the dollar as money because we trust the US secretary of the treasury in that the dollar will hold its value. Money allows us to convert, store, and transport wealth easily.</p>
<h1 id="so-what-even-is-bitcoin">So, what even is Bitcoin?</h1>
<p><strong>Bitcoin (shortened as BTC) is like a book.</strong> Transactions, the transfer of Bitcoin from one address to another are the lines in the book. Each page of the book can hold thousands of lines. Transactions do not become valid until a page with them is added to the book. Anyone can hold a copy of the book, and thousands of people do so already and are called nodes.</p>
<p>How do you add pages, or blocks, to the book? Once a page gets filled with lines, a special number, called the hash, is generated that depends on the transactions and the special number from the last page through an algorithm. Every line in the new page to be added is broadcasted to everyone who wants to contribute to the making of the book. Those people are called miners. In order to add a page to the book, you have to find the special number. When you find that special number, it is verified by the nodes. The only way to try and find this special number is to simply guess and then check. The algorithm also takes into account how fast the computers can find this special number and how many of them are online. It then changes its difficulty so that a page is added about every 10 minutes. The lucky miner who finds the correct special number gets a reward in the form of Bitcoin. The chance of you adding to the book depends on how powerful your computer is. Basically, everyone is guessing numbers as fast as they can until someone gets lucky. The guessing and checking is done on some form of a computer, so this reward incentivizes the book contributors to keep mining by typically covering their electrical costs.</p>
<p>After every chapter of the book is finished, the block reward, or the reward that comes from adding a page to the book, is halved. A new chapter is made every 210,000 pages, or about every four years. With the creation of bitcoin in 2008, this block reward used to be 50 BTC. Now, it is 6.25 BTC. These block rewards are the only way that new Bitcoin is put into circulation. When you perform a guess and check operation to try and find the special number, you currently have a 1 in 15 trillionth chance to guess correctly. It’s no longer profitable for everyday people like you and me to mine Bitcoin. Don’t worry. There are still plenty of other currencies to mine such as Ethereum or Ravencoin.</p>
<h1 id="cryptocurrencies-offer-several-advantages-over-conventional-money">Cryptocurrencies offer several advantages over conventional money.</h1>
<p>First, they diversify your portfolio. Governments tend to just print money when it is needed, often neglecting the risks of doing so and greatly impacting the economy. In Venezuela, CNBC reported that the overall inflation rate has recently reached over 10 million percent. We tend to think that our governments are stable, which is why we trust the dollar. But what happens if the government suddenly collapses, or loses its grip on reality? All those dollars would be completely useless. This is where the promise of cryptocurrencies such as Bitcoin come in. By their very nature, they are decentralized which makes them immune to government manipulation. Second, Bitcoin has a finite supply at 21 million BTC; you can’t just make more Bitcoins because of the block reward halving. Third, the blockchain, or the book, is always available to the public. This makes Bitcoin an anonymous yet transparent network in the sense that anyone can see the transactions, but cannot actually link the addresses to anyone’s identity. Thousands of nodes have a copy of the book, and since new pages depend on previous pages, it is resistant to hacking.</p>
<p>Another pro, or a con, depending on who you ask, is that Bitcoin can have any price, but no real value, since it isn’t backed by any physical asset. This makes Bitcoin extremely volatile. A problem with Bitcoin is that it is slow at handling transactions, about 7 transactions/sec compared to a maximum of 24,000 for VISA according to several sources. Another issue with Bitcoin is that it uses a lot of power, we’re talking as much as the eBay, Facebook, and Google servers combined. Since Bitcoin was the first cryptocurrency among thousands, newer ones address these problems.</p>
<h1 id="cryptocurrencies-can-bring-more-transparency-and-accountability-to-the-world">Cryptocurrencies can bring more transparency and accountability to the world.</h1>
<p>They hold a lot of potential in the future and there is no doubt that they will soon overtake the current economic system. That is, only if they are designed well. The anonymous founder of bitcoin, Satoshi Nakamoto once said:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“If you don’t believe it or don’t get it, I don’t have the time to try to convince you, sorry.”</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>EOLRC - Build Guide</title>
            <link>/posts/eolrc-build-guide/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 10:30:15 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/eolrc-build-guide/</guid>
            <description>Note that this is not a build guide of the car itself. Rather, how to integrate the 3D printed parts with the plane parts for your own projects.
Printing the parts The parts can be found in the plans GitHub repo.
I recommend printing the All_parts_arranged.stl
I used an Ultimaker 3 to print the parts with eSun PLA+ at a 0.2mm layer height at 215C, 35% infill, along with a PETG brim for easy cleanup.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Note that this is not a build guide of the car itself. Rather, how to integrate the 3D printed parts with the plane parts for your own projects.</p>
<h1 id="printing-the-parts">Printing the parts</h1>
<p><strong>The parts can be found in the <a href="https://github.com/NikolaiTeslovich/plans/tree/master/EOLRC">plans GitHub repo</a>.</strong></p>
<p>I recommend printing the All_parts_arranged.stl</p>
<p>I used an Ultimaker 3 to print the parts with eSun PLA+ at a 0.2mm layer height at 215C, 35% infill, along with a PETG brim for easy cleanup. They were printed relatively slow at 60mm/s.</p>
<p>The print took about an hour and a half and used under 20 grams of filament.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC1.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>3D printed parts fresh off the printer</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h1 id="bill-of-parts">Bill of parts</h1>
<ul>
<li><strong>Part (what I used)</strong></li>
<li>Battery (3S1P 2200mAh LiPo)</li>
<li>Electronic speed controller (BLHeli 20A brushless)</li>
<li>Motor with a 16mm by 19mm mounting screw arrangement (Flite Test Radial 2212-1050kV)</li>
<li>Radio receiver (FrSky X4R)</li>
<li>9g servo (some cheap one off Amazon)</li>
<li>All in one FPV camera (AKK 40CH 5.8G 0/25/50/200mW Switchable Micro AIO FPV Camera)</li>
<li>3D printed parts</li>
<li>Screws (All of these come with the servo and motor)
<ul>
<li>4x cone-shaped motor screws</li>
<li>2x long servo screws</li>
<li>1x short servo screw</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC2.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>Parts laid out</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h1 id="bill-of-tools">Bill of tools</h1>
<ul>
<li>Adjustable wrench</li>
<li>Phillips No. 1 screwdriver</li>
<li>Radio control transmitter/remote</li>
<li>FPV goggles with a 5.8GHz system</li>
</ul>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC3.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>Tools laid out</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h1 id="lets-put-the-parts-together-damn-it">Let&rsquo;s put the parts together damn it!</h1>
<h2 id="step-1---binding-the-receiver">Step 1 - Binding the receiver</h2>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC4.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>Sample binding circuit</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>Make a new model with zero trims. Check with your manufacturer&rsquo;s instructions on binding the radio with the receiver.</p>
<p>We&rsquo;ll need this for a later step.</p>
<h2 id="step-2---attaching-the-motor-to-axle-adapter-to-the-motor">Step 2 - Attaching the motor to axle adapter to the motor</h2>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC5.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h3 id="partstools">Parts/Tools</h3>
<ul>
<li>Motor with a 16mm by 19mm mounting arrangement</li>
<li>Motor to axle adapter</li>
<li>Adjustable wrench</li>
</ul>
<p>You can use additional tools for this, but be careful to <em><strong>not</strong></em> <strong>misshape the motor bell</strong>. I totally haven&rsquo;t done that before.</p>
<h3 id="steps">Steps</h3>
<ol>
<li>Screw on the motor to axle adapter onto the motor while making sure that it is screwed all the way down.</li>
</ol>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC6.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h2 id="step-3---affixing-the-motor-to-the-motor-mount">Step 3 - Affixing the motor to the motor mount</h2>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC7.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h3 id="partstools-1">Parts/Tools</h3>
<ul>
<li>Motor from step 2</li>
<li>Motor mount</li>
<li>4x cone-shaped motor screws</li>
<li>Philips No. 1 screwdriver</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="steps-1">Steps</h3>
<ol>
<li>Attach the motor to the motor mount using the screws</li>
</ol>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC8.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h2 id="step-4---mounting-the-servo-to-the-servo-holder">Step 4 - Mounting the servo to the servo holder</h2>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC9.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h3 id="partstools-2">Parts/Tools</h3>
<ul>
<li>9g servo</li>
<li>Servo mount</li>
<li>2x long servo screws</li>
<li>Philips No. 1 screwdriver</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="steps-2">Steps</h3>
<ol>
<li>Push the servo into the mount until it is flush</li>
<li>Screw in the screws to secure the Servo</li>
</ol>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC10.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h2 id="step-5---securing-the-servo-arm-to-the-servo">Step 5 - Securing the servo arm to the servo</h2>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC11.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h3 id="partstools-3">Parts/Tools</h3>
<ul>
<li>Radio receiver</li>
<li>Battery</li>
<li>Electronic speed controller</li>
<li>Servo assembly from step 4</li>
<li>Servo arm</li>
<li>1x short servo screw</li>
<li>Philips No. 1 screwdriver</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="steps-3">Steps</h3>
<ol>
<li>Plug the battery into the electronic speed controller</li>
<li>Power on the radio receiver using the electronic speed controller</li>
<li>Plug the servo wire into the second channel of the speed controller</li>
<li>Turn on the radio controller, it should connect to the radio receiver</li>
<li>Test that the servo works by moving the sticks on the controller</li>
<li>While leaving the sticks of the radio centered, line up the servo arm parallel to the long side of the servo mount and screw it in. (This is so that the servo arm is centered)</li>
</ol>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC12.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h2 id="step-6---fixing-the-aio-fpv-camera-to-the-camera-mount">Step 6 - Fixing the AIO FPV camera to the camera mount</h2>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC13.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h3 id="partstools-4">Parts/Tools</h3>
<ul>
<li>AIO FPV camera</li>
<li>Camera mount</li>
<li>Hot glue (optional)</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="steps-4">Steps</h3>
<ol>
<li>(Optional) Put hot glue inside the camera mount. This will secure the camera much more than just pushing it in and having it stay attached due to friction.</li>
<li>Carefully yet forcefully push the camera into the Camera mount. The camera lens should be flush with the exterior of the mount.</li>
</ol>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC14.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> 
</figure>

<h1 id="making-sure-that-the-whole-system-works">Making sure that the whole system works</h1>
<p>These gifs were recorded through the FPV camera, so at least I know that that works.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/controller.gif"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>Moving the controller&#39;s sticks</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>With everything properly wired up, it was time to test all the parts.</p>
<ul>
<li>The three motor cables were joined with the ones coming out of the electronic speed controller (ESC)</li>
<li>The ESC cable was plugged into the first channel of the receiver</li>
<li>The FPV camera was plugged into 5V BEC output of the ESC, for which I made a custom splitter</li>
<li>The servo cable was plugged into the second channel of the receiver</li>
<li>Obviously the battery was plugged into the ESC</li>
</ul>
<p>When I moved the left stick of the controller vertically, the motor span up. When I moved the right stick on the controller horizontally, the servo turned.</p>
<p><strong>If you want to reverse the motor direction, just swap any two of the three motor wires</strong></p>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/servomotor.gif"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>Servo and motor responding to my inputs</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h1 id="what-next">What next?</h1>
<p><strong>Congratulations, you&rsquo;re finally done. Now give yourself a big pat on the back</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Let your imagination run wild! As they say: the sky is the limit!</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="/posts/eolrc-an-extremely-overkill-lego-rc-car-from-plane-parts/">Here&rsquo;s what I built using these parts.</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>EOLRC - An Extremely Overkill LEGO RC Car (from Plane Parts)</title>
            <link>/posts/eolrc-an-extremely-overkill-lego-rc-car-from-plane-parts/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 07:27:42 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/eolrc-an-extremely-overkill-lego-rc-car-from-plane-parts/</guid>
            <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last played around with LEGO Technic. About 4 years to be exact. I can say with absolute confidence that this was my favorite way to spend time in my younger years.
I recollect building all sorts of crazy things from an automatic crossbow to a massive Mercedes Benz Unimog with a functioning suspension and a pneumatic crane. Over the years, I have acquired an impressive amount of LEGO technic parts that are still scattered everywhere around the house.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[
<div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
  <iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VaGnldsxeiA?autoplay=1" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" allowfullscreen title="YouTube Video"></iframe>
</div>

<h2 id="its-been-a-while">It&rsquo;s been a while</h2>
<p>since I last played around with LEGO Technic. About 4 years to be exact. I can say with absolute confidence that this was my favorite way to spend time in my
younger years.</p>
<p>I recollect building all sorts of crazy things from an automatic crossbow to a massive Mercedes Benz Unimog with a functioning suspension and a pneumatic crane. Over the years, I have acquired an impressive amount of LEGO technic parts that are still scattered everywhere around the house.</p>
<h2 id="i-recently-had-to-decommission">I recently had to decommission</h2>
<p>one of my favorite birds of all time. It was a <a href="https://www.flitetest.com/articles/ft-versa-wing">FT(Flite Test) Versa wing</a> with the <a href="https://www.flitetest.com/articles/blunt-nose-conversion-ft-versa-build">Blunt Nose modification</a>. It had to be put out of service due to a combination of old age and abuse like trying to hit a small gap between the trees.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/versa1.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>FT Blunt Nose Versa</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>This gave me several spare electronic components including a 20A BLHeli brushless ESC(electronic speed controller), a radio receiver, a Flite Test Radial 2212-1050kV motor, and an AIO(all in one) FPV camera.</p>
<h2 id="i-hopped-onto-fusion-360">I hopped onto Fusion 360</h2>
<p>and started modeling adapters to those electronic components so that they could be compatible with LEGO Technic. I&rsquo;ll be honest, it took multiple iterations to design parts that interfaced well with the plane and LEGO parts.</p>
<p>In the end, I designed and printed four parts: a servo holder so that the RC car could steer, a motor to lego axle adapter, a FPV camera holder, and last but not least a motor mount. Later on, I also designed an arm from the servo to the lego steering mechanism, but this is not in the pictures shown below.</p>
<p><strong>A build guide will also be written soon, so stay posted.</strong> <em><strong>Update</strong></em> <a href="/posts/eolrc-build-guide/">It&rsquo;s already written.</a></p>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/rclego1.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>3D printed parts</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure>
    <img src="/img/rclego2.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>3D printed parts with the electronics in them</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="here-is-the-final-result">Here is the final result:</h2>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/rclego3.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>The RC car in all its might</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure>
    <img src="/img/rclego4.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>The RC car at night</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="i-have-to-say">I have to say</h2>
<p>I am very impressed with the performance of this car. It has enough torque to just about climb over anything and on a 3S 2200mAh LiPo, the battery lasts for ages, about 1.5 hrs of regular use.</p>
<p>However, LEGO Technic clearly isn&rsquo;t designed for this. For instance, the lego axles heated up so much that they fused the gears onto them permanently. I sprayed the moving parts with WD-40, but that didn&rsquo;t seem to help too much.</p>
<p>I also did some water testing, and it seems to be surprisingly waterproof. <strong>Please don&rsquo;t abuse your electronics.</strong> I did it so that you wouldn&rsquo;t have to.</p>
<h2 id="what-are-its-features">What are its features?</h2>
<ul>
<li>A fully functioning differential</li>
<li>Optional 5mm led lights</li>
<li>FPV</li>
<li>Hella battery life</li>
<li>Quick and easy to build and repair after a crash</li>
<li>Customizability that comes with LEGO</li>
<li>Probably cheaper than buying the LEGO electronics</li>
<li>Extremely overpowered</li>
<li>Surprisingly waterproof</li>
<li>Extremely unstable</li>
<li>Brings back childhood nostalgia</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Let&#39;s Kill This MacBook! - How to Mine Monero on a Mac</title>
            <link>/posts/lets-kill-this-macbook-how-to-mine-monero-on-a-mac/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 10:04:55 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/lets-kill-this-macbook-how-to-mine-monero-on-a-mac/</guid>
            <description>MacBook Pro 13 without TouchBar   My good friend&amp;rsquo;s Mac is nearing its end He&amp;rsquo;s already had it, the one in the picture above, for a couple of years, and the battery is starting to degrade among several other serious issues. Since it is nearing its end soon, in the time that it isn&amp;rsquo;t being used it could mine some cryptocurrency.
MacBooks are known for their subpar cooling systems as demonstrated in this video.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<figure>
    <img src="/img/skylerdontlikemacs.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>MacBook Pro 13 without TouchBar</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h1 id="my-good-friends-mac-is-nearing-its-end">My good friend&rsquo;s Mac is nearing its end</h1>
<p>He&rsquo;s already had it, the one in the picture above, for a couple of years, and the battery is starting to degrade among several other serious issues. Since it is nearing its end soon, in the time that it isn&rsquo;t being used it could mine some cryptocurrency.</p>
<p>MacBooks are known for their subpar cooling systems as demonstrated in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MlOPPuNv4Ec">this video</a>. We are going to set up this mac for mining <a href="https://www.getmonero.org/">Monero(XMR)</a>, a type of cryptocurrency that can be mined with a CPU. He is only going to earn a couple pennies per day, but it&rsquo;s better than nothing. I don&rsquo;t know how he&rsquo;ll be able to sleep through the insane fan noise. Maybe he&rsquo;ll have to run an extension cable to his closet.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/monero.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>Official Monero Logo</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h1 id="disclaimer">Disclaimer</h1>
<p>You have been warned that there are risks such as damage to the computer keeping it at a high temperature for long periods of time.</p>
<p>It is barely profitable to do this on a laptop.</p>
<p>Pools usually have a minimum of 0.1 XMR payout, so it would take at least a couple of months to be able to withdraw the Monero if using a laptop.</p>
<p>Please do this at your own risk.</p>
<h1 id="installing-xmrig">Installing xmrig</h1>
<p><em><strong>Open the terminal application on your mac and copy and paste the code below into it, step by step.</strong></em></p>
<p>Install Homebrew, a package manager for macOS:</p>
<p><code>/bin/bash -c &quot;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/install.sh)&quot;</code></p>
<p>Install the required dependencies with Homebrew:</p>
<p><code>brew install git cmake libuv libmicrohttpd openssl hwloc</code></p>
<p>Clone, or in other words, save the xmrig mining software to your computer with git:</p>
<p><code>git clone https://github.com/xmrig/xmrig.git</code></p>
<p>Make the build directory inside of the xmrig directory:</p>
<p><code>mkdir xmrig/build</code></p>
<p>Navigate into the build directory inside xmrig:</p>
<p><code>cd xmrig/build</code></p>
<p>Build the program with cmake, then make:</p>
<p><code>cmake .. -DOPENSSL_ROOT_DIR=/usr/local/opt/openssl</code></p>
<p><code>make -j$(sysctl -n hw.logicalcpu)</code></p>
<h1 id="generating-the-xmrig-config-code">Generating the xmrig config code</h1>
<p>The people over at xmrig made a fantastic configuration wizard which helps create a line of code to start the miner.</p>
<p>Open the <a href="https://xmrig.com/wizard">xmrig configuration wizard</a></p>
<p>Click the <strong>New configuration</strong> button.</p>
<p>Press on the <strong>Add pool</strong> button.</p>
<p>Click on your pool of choice in the dropdown. I use the supporxmr.com pool.</p>
<p>Then there will be a pop-up where it asks for the <strong>Monero wallet address</strong>, where you type in your wallet. You can also choose to set a <strong>Worker name</strong>, something like MacBookPro13.</p>
<p>Navigate to the <strong>Backends</strong> tab and only turn on the <strong>CPU</strong> option. You can use a GPU if you have one, but I don&rsquo;t recommend it as there are far more profitable currencies to mine with a GPU.</p>
<p>Next, select the <strong>Misc</strong> tab and set a donation percentage, I chose to leave the <strong>HTTP API</strong> option off.</p>
<p>Finally, navigate the the <strong>Result</strong> tab, click on macOS option under the <strong>Command line</strong>. Copy the line of code.</p>
<h1 id="making-an-executable-shell-script">Making an executable shell script</h1>
<p>While this is not a required step, I recommend that you do it for ease of use.</p>
<p>Go back to the terminal app.</p>
<p>If it is still open, navigate to the user(<strong>~</strong>) directory:</p>
<p><code>cd .. &amp;&amp; cd ..</code></p>
<p>If you reopened it, double check that you are in the <strong>~</strong> directory.</p>
<p>Create a shell script called xmr:</p>
<p><code>touch xmr.sh</code></p>
<p>Make it executable:</p>
<p><code>chmod +x xmr.sh</code></p>
<p>Edit the shell script to make it navigate to the xmrig/build directory, and start the miner from there:</p>
<p><code>nano xmr.sh</code></p>
<p>A basic text editor will show up.</p>
<p>Type the following into it, each on a separate line:</p>
<p><code>cd xmrig/build</code></p>
<p><code>copy and paste the code that we generated earlier from the configurator</code></p>
<p>Press control x, press y to apply the changes, and then press enter to save the edits made to the file.</p>
<h1 id="running-the-shell-script">Running the shell script</h1>
<p>It&rsquo;s actually really easy, type the following into terminal from the <strong>~</strong> directory, which is the default when you open Terminal:</p>
<p><code>./xmr.sh</code></p>
<p>To stop the program press control c.</p>
<p>You can monitor all sorts of statistics on the pool&rsquo;s home page, logging in with your wallet address as your username.</p>
<h1 id="updating-xmrig">Updating xmrig</h1>
<p>Navigate to the build directory:</p>
<p><code>cd xmrig/build</code></p>
<p>Update using the git pull command:</p>
<p><code>git pull</code></p>
<h1 id="resources">Resources</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Based around the <a href="https://xmrig.com/docs/miner/macos-build">official xmrig macOS build guide</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://coin360.com/coin/monero-xmr">Monero(XMR) price chart</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.getmonero.org/">Monero&rsquo;s official website</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My First Post</title>
            <link>/posts/my-first-post/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 15:21:48 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
            <description>Hello World!
Why did I make this website and what even is it? I&amp;rsquo;m glad you asked although you probably didn&amp;rsquo;t! I made and will continue to make this website because I want to learn how to build a website. I also enjoy writing, especially when it isn&amp;rsquo;t tied to a grade.
I will be posting about everything from a small cryptocurrency mining operation that I run in the basement to my favorite hobby of RC flight to my own ice cream recipes and everything in between.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello World!</p>
<h2 id="why-did-i-make-this-website-and-what-even-is-it">Why did I make this website and what even is it?</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;m glad you asked although you probably didn&rsquo;t! I made and <strong>will continue</strong> to make this website because I want to learn how to build a website. I also enjoy writing, especially when it isn&rsquo;t tied to a grade.</p>
<p>I will be posting about everything from a small cryptocurrency mining operation that I run in the basement to my favorite hobby of RC flight to my own ice cream recipes and everything in between. In short, the things that I do to keep myself sane, especially during quarantine. I&rsquo;ll post at least every week. This is my blog site.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
