<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Nikolai Nekrutenko</title>
        <link>/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Nikolai Nekrutenko</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 07:27:42 -0400</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>An Extremely Overkill LEGO RC Car from Airplane Parts</title>
            <link>/posts/an-extremely-overkill-lego-rc-car-from-airplane-parts/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 07:27:42 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/an-extremely-overkill-lego-rc-car-from-airplane-parts/</guid>
            <description>This article is not yet complete, just publishing it for testing purposes
It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last played around with LEGO Technic. About 4 years to be exact. I can say with absolute confidence that this was my favorite way to spend time in my younger years.
I recollect building all sorts of crazy things from an automatic lego crossbow to a massive Mercedes Benz Unimog with a working suspension and a functioning pneumatic crane.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>This article is not yet complete, just publishing it for testing purposes</strong></p>
<h2 id="its-been-a-while">It&rsquo;s been a while</h2>
<p>since I last played around with LEGO Technic. About 4 years to be exact. I can say with absolute confidence that this was my favorite way to spend time in my
younger years.</p>
<p>I recollect building all sorts of crazy things from an automatic lego crossbow to a massive Mercedes Benz Unimog with a working suspension and a functioning pneumatic crane. Over the years, I have acquired an impressive amount of LEGO technic parts that are still scattered around the house.</p>
<h2 id="i-recently-had-to-decommission">I recently had to decommission</h2>
<p>one of my favorite birds of all time. It was a FT(Flite Test) Versa wing with the Blunt Nose modification, and it had to be put out of service due to a combination of old age and abuse like trying to hit a small gap between the trees.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/versa1.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>FT Blunt Nose Versa</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>This gave me several spare electronic components including a 20A BLHeli brushless ESC(electronic speed controller), a radio receiver, a Flite Test Radial 2212-1050kV motor, and an AIO(all in one) FPV camera.</p>
<h2 id="i-hopped-onto-fusion-360">I hopped onto Fusion 360</h2>
<p>and started modeling adapters to those electronic components so that they could be compatible with LEGO Technic. I&rsquo;ll be honest, it took multiple iterations to design parts that interfaced well with the plane and LEGO parts.</p>
<p>In the end, I designed and printed four parts: a servo holder so that the RC car could steer, a motor to lego axle adapter, a FPV camera holder, and last but not least a motor mount.</p>
<p>They were all printed in PLA with a 0.2mm layer height and 35% infill. The servo was some crappy 9g off of amazon, but it works fine for this application.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/rclego1.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>3D printed parts</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure>
    <img src="/img/rclego2.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>3D printed parts with the electronics in them</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<p>I forgot to consider how to actually make the servo steer, so an additional part was designed for that.</p>
<p><strong>Here is the final result:</strong></p>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/rclego3.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>The RC car in all its might</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<figure>
    <img src="/img/rclego4.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>The RC car at night</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="i-have-to-say">I have to say</h2>
<p>I am very impressed with the performance of this car. It has enough torque to just about climb over anything and on a 3S 2200mAh LiPo, the battery lasts for ages, about 1.5 hrs of regular use.</p>
<p>However, LEGO Technic clearly isn&rsquo;t designed for this. For instance, the lego axles heated up so much that they fused the gears on them permanently. I sprayed the moving parts with WD-40, but that didn&rsquo;t seem to help too much for some reason.</p>
<h2 id="what-are-its-features">What are it&rsquo;s features?</h2>
<ul>
<li>A fully functioning differential</li>
<li>Optional 5mm led lights</li>
<li>FPV</li>
<li>Hella battery life</li>
<li>Quick and easy to build and repair after a crash</li>
<li>Customizability that comes with LEGO</li>
<li>Probably cheaper than buying the LEGO electronics</li>
<li>Insane torque</li>
<li>Extremely unstable</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Let&#39;s Kill This MacBook! - How to Mine Monero on a Mac</title>
            <link>/posts/lets-kill-this-macbook-how-to-mine-monero-on-a-mac/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 10:04:55 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/lets-kill-this-macbook-how-to-mine-monero-on-a-mac/</guid>
            <description>MacBook Pro 13 without TouchBar   My good friend wants to kill his MacBook He&amp;rsquo;s already had it, the one in the picture above, for a couple of years, and the battery is starting to degrade among several other serious issues. He has a decent budget for a new computer, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to buy a new laptop until this one stops functioning.
We are going to destroy the MacBook by heat over the next few weeks.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<figure>
    <img src="/img/skylerdontlikemacs.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>MacBook Pro 13 without TouchBar</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="my-good-friend-wants-to-kill-his-macbook">My good friend wants to kill his MacBook</h2>
<p>He&rsquo;s already had it, the one in the picture above, for a couple of years, and the battery is starting to degrade among several other serious issues. He has a decent budget for a new computer, but doesn&rsquo;t want to buy a new laptop until this one stops functioning.</p>
<p>We are going to destroy the MacBook by <strong>heat</strong> over the next few weeks. MacBooks are known for their subpar cooling systems as demonstrated in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MlOPPuNv4Ec">this video</a>. Instead of wasting this Mac&rsquo;s <strong>insane</strong> computational power, we are going to set it up for mining <a href="https://www.getmonero.org/">Monero(XMR)</a>, a type of cryptocurrency that can be mined with a CPU. He is only going to earn a couple pennies per day, but it&rsquo;s better than nothing. I don&rsquo;t know how he&rsquo;ll be able to sleep through the insane fan noise. Maybe he&rsquo;ll have to run an extension cable to his closet.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="/img/monero.png"
         alt="Hello Friend"/> <figcaption>
            <h4>Official Monero Logo</h4>
        </figcaption>
</figure>

<h2 id="disclaimer">Disclaimer</h2>
<p>You have been warned that there are risks such as damage to the computer keeping it at a high temperature for long periods of time.</p>
<p>It is barely profitable to do this on a laptop.</p>
<p>Pools usually have a minimum of 0.1 XMR payout, so it would take at least a couple of months to be able to withdraw the Monero if using a laptop.</p>
<p>Please do this at your own risk.</p>
<h2 id="installing-xmrig">Installing xmrig</h2>
<p><em><strong>Open the terminal application on your mac and copy and paste the code below into it, step by step.</strong></em></p>
<p>Install Homebrew, a package manager for macOS:</p>
<p><code>/bin/bash -c &quot;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/install.sh)&quot;</code></p>
<p>Install the required dependencies with Homebrew:</p>
<p><code>brew install git cmake libuv libmicrohttpd openssl hwloc</code></p>
<p>Clone, or in other words, save the xmrig mining software to your computer with git:</p>
<p><code>git clone https://github.com/xmrig/xmrig.git</code></p>
<p>Make the build directory inside of the xmrig directory:</p>
<p><code>mkdir xmrig/build</code></p>
<p>Navigate into the build directory inside xmrig:</p>
<p><code>cd xmrig/build</code></p>
<p>Build the program with cmake, then make:</p>
<p><code>cmake .. -DOPENSSL_ROOT_DIR=/usr/local/opt/openssl</code></p>
<p><code>make -j$(sysctl -n hw.logicalcpu)</code></p>
<h2 id="generating-the-xmrig-config-code">Generating the xmrig config code</h2>
<p>The people over at xmrig made a fantastic configuration wizard which helps create a line of code to start the miner.</p>
<p>Open the <a href="https://xmrig.com/wizard">xmrig configuration wizard</a></p>
<p>Click the <strong>New configuration</strong> button.</p>
<p>Press on the <strong>Add pool</strong> button.</p>
<p>Click on your pool of choice in the dropdown. I use the supporxmr.com pool.</p>
<p>Then there will be a pop-up where it asks for the <strong>Monero wallet address</strong>, where you type in your wallet. You can also choose to set a <strong>Worker name</strong>, something like MacBookPro13.</p>
<p>Navigate to the <strong>Backends</strong> tab and only turn on the <strong>CPU</strong> option. You can use a GPU if you have one, but I don&rsquo;t recommend it as there are far more profitable currencies to mine with a GPU.</p>
<p>Next, select the <strong>Misc</strong> tab and set a donation percentage, I chose to leave the <strong>HTTP API</strong> option off.</p>
<p>Finally, navigate the the <strong>Result</strong> tab, click on macOS option under the <strong>Command line</strong>. Copy the line of code.</p>
<h2 id="making-an-executable-shell-script">Making an executable shell script</h2>
<p>While this is not a required step, I recommend that you do it for ease of use.</p>
<p>Go back to the terminal app.</p>
<p>If it is still open, navigate to the user(<strong>~</strong>) directory:</p>
<p><code>cd .. &amp;&amp; cd ..</code></p>
<p>If you reopened it, double check that you are in the <strong>~</strong> directory.</p>
<p>Create a shell script called xmr:</p>
<p><code>touch xmr.sh</code></p>
<p>Make it executable:</p>
<p><code>chmod +x xmr.sh</code></p>
<p>Edit the shell script to make it navigate to the xmrig/build directory, and start the miner from there:</p>
<p><code>nano xmr.sh</code></p>
<p>A basic text editor will show up.</p>
<p>Type the following into it, each on a separate line:</p>
<p><code>cd xmrig/build</code></p>
<p><code>copy and paste the code that we generated earlier from the configurator</code></p>
<p>Press control x, press y to apply the changes, and then press enter to save the edits made to the file.</p>
<h2 id="running-the-shell-script">Running the shell script</h2>
<p>It&rsquo;s actually really easy, type the following into terminal from the <strong>~</strong> directory, which is the default when you open Terminal:</p>
<p><code>./xmr.sh</code></p>
<p>To stop the program press control c.</p>
<p>You can monitor all sorts of statistics on the pool&rsquo;s home page, logging in with your wallet address as your username.</p>
<h2 id="updating-xmrig">Updating xmrig</h2>
<p>Navigate to the build directory:</p>
<p><code>cd xmrig/build</code></p>
<p>Update using the git pull command:</p>
<p><code>git pull</code></p>
<h2 id="resources">Resources</h2>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Based around the <a href="https://xmrig.com/docs/miner/macos-build">official xmrig macOS build guide</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://coin360.com/coin/monero-xmr">Monero(XMR) price chart</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.getmonero.org/">Monero&rsquo;s official website</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My First Post</title>
            <link>/posts/my-first-post/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 15:21:48 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
            <description>Hello World!
Why did I make this website and what even is it? I&amp;rsquo;m glad you asked although you probably didn&amp;rsquo;t! I made and will continue to make this website because I want to learn how to build a website. I also enjoy writing, especially when it isn&amp;rsquo;t tied to a grade.
I will be posting about everything from a small cryptocurrency mining operation that I run in the basement to my favorite hobby of RC flight to my own ice cream recipes and everything in between.</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello World!</p>
<h2 id="why-did-i-make-this-website-and-what-even-is-it">Why did I make this website and what even is it?</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;m glad you asked although you probably didn&rsquo;t! I made and <strong>will continue</strong> to make this website because I want to learn how to build a website. I also enjoy writing, especially when it isn&rsquo;t tied to a grade.</p>
<p>I will be posting about everything from a small cryptocurrency mining operation that I run in the basement to my favorite hobby of RC flight to my own ice cream recipes and everything in between. In short, the things that I do to keep myself sane, especially during quarantine. I&rsquo;ll post at least every week. This is my blog site.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
