<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <channel>
        <title>Posts on Nikolai Nekrutenko</title>
        <link>//localhost:1313/posts/</link>
        <description>Recent content in Posts on Nikolai Nekrutenko</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
        <language>en</language>
        <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 16:50:50 +0100</lastBuildDate>
        <atom:link href="//localhost:1313/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
        
        <item>
            <title>How to Make Windows Install Media on MacOS</title>
            <link>//localhost:1313/posts/how-to-make-windows-install-media-on-macos/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 16:50:50 +0100</pubDate>
            
            <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/how-to-make-windows-install-media-on-macos/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Creating a bootable, functional windows installation media is done wrongly in so many of the guides I checked, that it can truly send someone down a rabbit hole of confusion figuring what messed up. It took me several attempts and countless hours to finally figure out a way that works.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;So, let us begin:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note:&lt;/em&gt; All command-line formatted entries like the one below will need to be run in terminal.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Creating a bootable, functional windows installation media is done wrongly in so many of the guides I checked, that it can truly send someone down a rabbit hole of confusion figuring what messed up. It took me several attempts and countless hours to finally figure out a way that works.</p>
<p><strong>So, let us begin:</strong></p>
<p><em>Note:</em> All command-line formatted entries like the one below will need to be run in terminal.</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>Just copy and paste into terminal
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>First of all, the latest Windows 10 Recovery Image needs to be downloaded from <a href="https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/software-download/windows10ISO">Microsoft&rsquo;s website</a>.</p>
<p>Select the version, language and either the 64 or 32 bit version depending on your system (most likely the 64 bit version).</p>
<p>While that is downloading, there is something that you must know, which may offend you. Windows, Microsoft in particular, is dumb.</p>
<p>Let me elaborate: For some reason, they decided to make the <code>install.wim</code> file larger than 4GB, the file size limit for the FAT format which our drive is now formatted in. So, we have to split this file up into two pieces, which requires special software called <a href="https://wimlib.net">wimlib</a>.</p>
<p>I strongly suggest installing wimlib with <a href="https://brew.sh">Homebrew</a>, a truly amazing package manager for MacOS:</p>
<p>If you don&rsquo;t already have Homebrew installed:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>/bin/bash -c <span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;</span><span style="color:#66d9ef">$(</span>curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/HEAD/install.sh<span style="color:#66d9ef">)</span><span style="color:#e6db74">&#34;</span>
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Install wimlib:</p>
<div class="highlight"><pre tabindex="0" style="color:#f8f8f2;background-color:#272822;-moz-tab-size:4;-o-tab-size:4;tab-size:4;"><code class="language-bash" data-lang="bash"><span style="display:flex;"><span>brew install wimlib
</span></span></code></pre></div><p>Once that is downloaded, click on the downloaded file to mount it. In a sense, we are attaching it like a thumb-drive to copy data from it to our actual usb stick or other kind of storage drive. Anything that can be plugged into the computer that windows is going to be installed on is fair game and will be referred to as an installation media throughout this guide.</p>
<p>Alternatively, the following command can be run</p>
<p>Next, we will use the MacOS terminal to find and format the external drive that will be our installation media.</p>
<p>Then, run the following command:</p>
<p>There&rsquo;s no harm in running it if you&rsquo;re not sure, it&rsquo;ll let you know if you already having it before going ahead with the install.</p>
<p>Go grab a coffee or tea, or go on a walk while the files are copied over to the external storage media, particularly if using an old USB drive.</p>
<p>Now go and enjoy your windows machine for whatever your mac apparently isn&rsquo;t already good enough.</p>
<p>This guide was greatly inspired by <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=ZVW7FyIEoDQ&amp;list=PLWoHVszdLgEzdxylAmHhAVaxHe-1BfzpT&amp;index=9&amp;t=337s">this youtube video</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>How to Build a Website: A Guide for Command-Line Novices</title>
            <link>//localhost:1313/posts/how-to-build-a-website-a-guide-for-command-line-novices/</link>
            <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 10:38:15 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/how-to-build-a-website-a-guide-for-command-line-novices/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Formerly titled: How to Build a Website for Your Studio (or Anything): A Step by Step Guide&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/img/BBEssay/helloworld.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Hello World&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px;&#34;  /&gt;

        
    &lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This guide is intended for Macintosh users who have never programmed before. With a bit of searching, the same steps can easily be applied to Windows and Linux machines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most will agree that a book is judged by its cover—for better or worse. Websites are the covers of your studio, organization, or even yourself, which are the books. Well-constructed websites build credibility and legitimacy. They are the bridge between your members and the outer world. A good-looking, well functioning website is essential to making your mark in the modern world. In contrast, a poorly built website can have the opposite effect, negatively affecting your reputation.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Formerly titled: How to Build a Website for Your Studio (or Anything): A Step by Step Guide</strong></p>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/BBEssay/helloworld.png"  alt="Hello World"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h1 id="introduction">Introduction</h1>
<p>This guide is intended for Macintosh users who have never programmed before. With a bit of searching, the same steps can easily be applied to Windows and Linux machines.</p>
<p>Most will agree that a book is judged by its cover—for better or worse. Websites are the covers of your studio, organization, or even yourself, which are the books. Well-constructed websites build credibility and legitimacy. They are the bridge between your members and the outer world. A good-looking, well functioning website is essential to making your mark in the modern world. In contrast, a poorly built website can have the opposite effect, negatively affecting your reputation.</p>
<p>The key to a great first website is simplicity and understanding how all of the gears of the machine mesh together. Like learning a hyung for the first time, this guide will give you the order and intended moves. It is up to you, however, to experiment and envision applications for these moves. Following this guide, you will build a great, simple website for anything you want to using the <a href="https://github.com/rhazdon/hugo-theme-hello-friend-ng">Hello Friend NG theme by Djordje Atlialp</a>.</p>
<p>If you’ve never used the command line, there’s nothing to be afraid of. I guarantee you it will soon become your preferred way of doing things.</p>
<h1 id="part-1-initial-setup">Part 1: Initial Setup</h1>
<p>The website made from guide can be viewed at: <a href="https://inspiring-thompson-3f793d.netlify.app">https://inspiring-thompson-3f793d.netlify.app</a></p>
<p>The repository I made following this guide is at: <a href="https://github.com/NikolaiTeslovich/testsite">https://github.com/NikolaiTeslovich/testsite</a></p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>The first step is to go to <a href="https://github.com/">GitHub</a> and sign up for an account, which is where the website will be stored on the cloud. GitHub is an online implementation of Git, which is a version control system. A version control system is a kind of software that helps the developer efficiently communicate and track all the changes that have been made to the code, or website in our scenario. Since it tracks every change, any of the changes can be undone, this means that you shouldn’t be discouraged to play around with your website!</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Once you have your account created in GitHub, make a repository by pressing the “new” button. A repository is a folder to store your project in. Pick a repository name that is brief. The description can be filled if you would like. I suggest making the repository public, but it won’t affect the website’s functionality. A README file (in which you can document your project) is not necessary. Please choose an appropriate license. If you want to open-source everything, use the MIT license. For more information about licenses, visit <a href="https://choosealicense.com/">https://choosealicense.com/</a>.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>With that done, open the Terminal application. Here is what it looks like:</p>
</li>
</ol>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/BBEssay/terminal.png"  alt="Mac OS Terminal"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<p><strong>Code starting with a “&gt;” should be copied and pasted into the Terminal, followed by pressing the “enter” key. Code without the “&gt;” should be edited in a code editor.</strong></p>
<ol start="4">
<li>Before we can use Terminal to its full potential, some tools need to be installed that will allow us to make the website. You will be asked for your password, and this process will take several minutes. Go outside, for once, while you wait for this to complete. The first tool being Xcode, which is installed with:</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&gt; xcode-select --install
</code></pre><ol start="5">
<li>Next, we will install Homebrew, which is an open-source package manager. In other words, it automates the process of installing and keeping software up to date. Install it with the following command:</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&gt; /bin/bash -c &#34;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/HEAD/install.sh)&#34;
</code></pre><ol start="6">
<li>A static website contains web pages with fixed content, so each page displays the same information to every visitor. Static sites are the most basic type of website and are the easiest to create. Let’s install Hugo, an open-source static site generator, which is the skeleton of the website:</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&gt; brew install hugo
</code></pre><ol start="7">
<li>Then, we need something to edit the code with! While we could use something like TextEdit, using a tool specifically designed for the job—such as a dedicated code editor—is better. I recommend Atom, but Visual Studio Code works just as well. After deciding which one you’d like to use, instead of manually downloading it and going through the installer, either can also be installed with Homebrew:</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&gt; brew install --cask atom or  &gt; brew install --cask visual-studio-code
</code></pre><h1 id="part-2-creating-and-working-on-your-website">Part 2: Creating and Working on Your Website</h1>
<ol>
<li>Duplicate (clone) the repository onto your computer. Use the url in the search bar of your web browser as the “repository-link”:</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&gt; git clone repository-link
</code></pre><ol start="2">
<li>Create a folder for your website with Hugo (name it in one word for simplicity):</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&gt; hugo new site mysite --force
</code></pre><p>If you accidentally make a mistake in your spelling, the folder can be removed with:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&gt; rm -rf mysite or &gt; rm -rf &#39;my site&#39;
</code></pre><ol start="3">
<li>Enter the project folder through the terminal:</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&gt; cd mysite
</code></pre><p>“cd” is a way of telling Terminal to go into a folder, which in my case is the “mysite” folder. For more information about these, and other useful commands to do all sorts of things with folders, visit: <a href="https://www.javatpoint.com/linux-directories">https://www.javatpoint.com/linux-directories</a></p>
<ol start="4">
<li>We will import the theme into the project folder as a submodule. All we are doing in this step is linking the theme project inside of your website, meaning that everything inside of that folder will be up to date, which is good for bug fixes and security improvements:</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&gt; git submodule add https://GitHub.com/rhazdon/hugo-theme-hello-friend-ng.git themes/hello-friend-ng
</code></pre><ol start="5">
<li>Let’s start up your website! While still in the repository’s folder, we’re going to start Hugo and access the website locally, meaning that it is not online yet:</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code class="language->" data-lang=">">To learn more about Hugo commands, visit: https://gohugo.io/getting-started/usage/
</code></pre><ol start="6">
<li>
<p>To view the website on your web browser, visit the local port at <a href="http://localhost:1313/">http://localhost:1313/</a>. It will update with every change you make in the code editor.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>If at any point you need to type something into the command line while the server is running, like when you want to make a new post or publish the website, press “control” and “c” at the same time on your keyboard to stop the server. The server can be resumed the same way that it was started in step 5.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Now, you will surely notice that something is off. Is it a blank page? Yes it is, because we never touched the config.toml file. This is the place where you tell Hugo how to show and configure the website. So, in your code editor, open up the website project and navigate to config.toml. This is what it should look like:</p>
</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>baseURL = &#34;http://example.org/&#34;
languageCode = &#34;en-us&#34;
title = &#34;My New Hugo Site&#34;
… there is barely anything there.
</code></pre><ol start="9">
<li>
<p>To fix this, in the place of these three lines, simply copy and paste the example configuration file on page 15. Don’t forget to save the now edited file so that the website updates. The code is commented, for your experimentation and understanding.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Great, you have a front page, but not much else. What good is a website without any content, just like what good is a hyung without strong stances? Let’s create a first blog post and call it hello-world:</p>
</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&gt; hugo new posts/hello-world.md
</code></pre><ol start="11">
<li>Now, navigate to the hello-world post in your code editor, which is in the content, then post folder. You’ll see that there is this interesting heading, with the title, time, and other options:</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>---
title: &#34;Hello World&#34;
date: 2021-07-11T17:52:30-04:00
draft: true
toc: false
images:
tags:
  - untagged
---
</code></pre><ol start="12">
<li>The title is pretty self-explanatory. The date was the exact time when you entered the command in step 10, to create the “Hello World” post. The draft option is what hides or shows this post to the world when we make the website live. Table of Contents is short for toc, the images option can be ignored, and you should add a tag, or a few, if you want.</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="part-3-writing-content-in-markdown">Part 3: Writing Content in Markdown</h1>
<p>Using Markdown is different than using an application like Microsoft Word, where you click buttons to format words and phrases, and the changes are visible immediately. When you create a Markdown-formatted file, you add Markdown code to the text to indicate which words and phrases should look different. A piece of software, such as Hugo, interprets this notation and makes it look as intended on your website. Here is a little table inspired by <a href="https://www.markdownguide.org/cheat-sheet/">Markdown Guide’s Cheat Sheet</a>:</p>
<table>
  <thead>
      <tr>
          <th>Element</th>
          <th>Markdown Code</th>
          <th>Markdown Appearance</th>
      </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody>
      <tr>
          <td>italicized</td>
          <td><code>*italicized*</code></td>
          <td><em>italicized</em></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>bold</td>
          <td><code>**bold**</code></td>
          <td><strong>bold</strong></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>italicized &amp; bold</td>
          <td><code>***italicized &amp; bold***</code></td>
          <td><em><strong>italicized &amp; bold</strong></em></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>headings</td>
          <td><code># heading 1</code></td>
          <td># heading 1</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td></td>
          <td><code>## heading 2</code></td>
          <td>## heading 2</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td></td>
          <td><code>### heading 3</code></td>
          <td>### heading 3</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>code</td>
          <td><code>this is already code</code></td>
          <td><code>code</code></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>lines of code</td>
          <td><code>```</code></td>
          <td>will not render in a table</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td></td>
          <td><code>lines</code></td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td></td>
          <td><code>of code</code></td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td></td>
          <td><code>```</code></td>
          <td></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>blockquote</td>
          <td><code>&gt; block quote</code></td>
          <td>will not render in a table</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>list</td>
          <td><code>- one</code></td>
          <td>- one</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td></td>
          <td><code>- two</code></td>
          <td>- two</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td></td>
          <td><code>- three</code></td>
          <td>- three</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>ordered list</td>
          <td><code>1. first</code></td>
          <td>1. first</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td></td>
          <td><code>2. second</code></td>
          <td>2. second</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td></td>
          <td><code>3. third</code></td>
          <td>3. third</td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>link</td>
          <td><code>[title](http://www.example.com)</code></td>
          <td><a href="http://www.example.com">title</a></td>
      </tr>
      <tr>
          <td>image</td>
          <td><code>![](path/to/image.png)</code></td>
          <td><img src="/img/BBEssay/helloworldsmall.png" alt=""></td>
      </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>
<p>Applying this to the “Hello World” post, there are no limits to our creativity:</p>
<p><img src="/img/BBEssay/helloworldpage.png" alt=""></p>
<p>hello-world.md looks like this:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>---
title: &#34;Hello World&#34;
date: 2021-07-11T17:52:30-04:00
draft: true
toc: false
images:
tags:
  - firstpost
---

# Wow,

I just wrote the *first* **post** of [this ***website***](/).

- In a few
- short steps
- a **beautiful**
- website was born

&gt; A book really is judged by its cover for better or for worse

`Now this wasn&#39;t that hard, now was it?`

![](/img/wtsda.png)
</code></pre><h1 id="part-4-about-the-structure-of-our-website">Part 4: About the Structure of Our Website</h1>
<p>Here is the structure of the website so far (I’ve omitted some things for clarity). The items with the asterisk in from of them (*) are the things that we’ve edited or created apart from the original website structure:</p>
<p>How to interpret this chart:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>.  — the . means the current directory or folder.
├── folder2 (/folder2)
│   └── folder3 (/folder2/folder3)
│       └── image.png (/folder2/folder3/image.png) — image.png is in
folder 3, which is in folder 2, which is in the current directory.
</code></pre><p>For our website:</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>.
├── archetypes
├── *config.toml
├── content
│   └── *posts
│       └── *hello-world.md
├── data
├── layouts
├── resources
├── static
│   └── *img
│       └── *wtsda.png
└── themes
    └── hello-friend-ng
</code></pre><p>Looking back at our “Hello World” post, Markdown was used to insert the image—<code>![](/img/wtsda.png)</code>. Hugo defaults to the static folder as a place for items that can be inserted, like images. I made an image folder and names it <code>img</code> for organizational purposes. Then, I dragged the image into that folder with the Finder application. As a result, the path for the Markdown code was <code>/img/wtsda.png</code> instead of <code>static/img/wtsda.png</code>.</p>
<p>The “Hello World” post itself has the path <code>/content/posts/hello-world.md</code>. Just like for the image, however, Hugo defaults to the content folder as the place for pages and blog posts. So, in reality it is <code>posts/hello-world.md</code>. This can be seen in the command we used to create the post (don’t run this command again, I just put it in below as a reference):</p>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&gt; hugo new posts/hello-world.md
</code></pre><h1 id="part-5-making-an-about-page">Part 5: Making an About Page</h1>
<p>What’s the use of having a website without an “About” page to explain what you or your organization is? There would be no credibility without one. So it is only natural to make one.</p>
<ol>
<li>Similar to making the “Hello World” post, we are going to use a Hugo command to create your “About” page:</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&gt; hugo new about.md
</code></pre><ol start="2">
<li>How can we actually look at this page, since it isn’t a post? Well, we have to edit our config.toml, so that it displays an “About” in the menu bar. Edit the end of the config.toml, just under the command which creates a menu:</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>  	[[menu.main]]
   	 identifier = &#34;blog&#34;
   	 name       = &#34;Blog&#34;
   	 url        = &#34;/posts&#34;
# Here is the part we are adding:
# Make sure it’s indented correctly!
[[menu.main]]
 	 identifier = &#34;about&#34;
  	 name       = &#34;About&#34;
  	 url        = &#34;/about&#34;
</code></pre><ol start="3">
<li>Then, just like we did for the “Hello World” post, write some content for it in Markdown.</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="part-6-backing-up-updating--deploying-your-website">Part 6: Backing up, Updating &amp; Deploying your Website</h1>
<p>With that out of the way, your website is fully functional—only on your computer, that is! We have to publish it, or in other words, make it live for the world to see.</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>First of all, change the draft: true to draft: false in the header of the posts and pages that you want everyone to see.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>We need to manually add the files for git to see them:</p>
</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&gt; git add .
</code></pre><ol start="3">
<li>Then, git needs to know that this is a commit, or in other words, a save of the data. Write a message so that it’s easier to reference later, should any mistakes come up.</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&gt; git commit -m &#39;your message&#39;
</code></pre><ol start="4">
<li>Upload (push) the data to your repository:</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&gt; git push
</code></pre><p>We still need to figure out how to actually make it live, since right now, it’s just sitting in that repository as a bunch of code and files. Fortunately, there is this tool called Netlify, which uses data from the GitHub repository, to make a website which updates everytime you push new data to your repository.</p>
<ol start="5">
<li>
<p>Go make an account on <a href="netlify.com">Netlify</a>, signing up with your GitHub.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Next, to actually make the website, press the “New site from Git” button. Then select our single repository, and leave all the options at their defaults. And we should have a working website? But when we click on the link Netlify has provided for us, nothing comes up. That’s because there is a thing left to change in config.toml.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>How about we change the link to something that we can actually remember, before editing the config.toml. You can make a custom link for free with Netlify, buy one from a service such as Google, or use one that you already own. To change the domain through Netlify, click on the “Domain Settings” button, then press the “Options” button, and change the domain from there. If you own, or have just bought your own domain, press the “Add custom domain” button.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>In config.toml, edit the “baseurl” line by changing “localhost” to the link you are using for your site:</p>
</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>From: baseurl = &#34;localhost&#34;  
To: baseurl = http://my-new-url.org
</code></pre><ol start="9">
<li>Now, push those changes again using steps 1-3. Now you website should be live and functional! It also looks just as good, if not better, on your phone.</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="part-7-restoring-and-modifying-your-website-in-the-future">Part 7: Restoring and Modifying your Website in the Future</h1>
<p>What if on one fine day your computer just crashes permanently. What if you just accidentally, or purposefully close Terminal and the code editor. It may seem like all of your progress is forever lost. How do you revert to the state you had previously, to continuing working on your amazing, new website?</p>
<ol>
<li>
<p>If you haven’t worked on your website in a while, and something happened to your computer, that caused you to reinstall the operating system, repeat “Part 1: Initial Setup” being sure to skip steps 1 and 2. Those first steps are skipped because you did them already, and they’re safe on the cloud. With all of the tools installed again, continue to the next step.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>Otherwise, with Terminal and the code editors open again, enter into the project’s repository with the following command:</p>
</li>
</ol>
<pre tabindex="0"><code>&gt; cd mysite
</code></pre><ol start="3">
<li>
<p>Start the website following steps 5-7 in “Part 2: Creating and Working on the Website”.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>After you are content with the edits you’ve made, follow steps 1-4 keeping in “Part 6: Backing up, Updating &amp; Deploying your Website”.</p>
</li>
<li>
<p>That’s it, repeat these steps should anything happen. Eventually, with enough practice, all of this will become muscle memory.</p>
</li>
</ol>
<h1 id="the-end">The End</h1>
<p><em>Note: this ending is intended for my target audience, the World Tang Soo Do Association testing panel, which will test me for black belt in Septmber of 2021. This is why some of the terms are in Korean and are not easily relatable to others.</em></p>
<p>With the first version of your website successfully published, give yourself a pat on the back!</p>
<p>After hours, or even days of blood, sweat, and tears, you have successfully learned the moves in the Sae Kye Hyungs of website building by making a beautiful, and at the same time, functional website all by yourself! You are that one in a hundred Gup student who persevered despite the difficulties and stuck with Tang Soo Do, becoming a Cho Dan. Except in addition to Tang Soo Do, you managed to build a website that actually works, and you mostly understand how and why it functions!</p>
<p>Now it is up to you to pass the probationary period, and ascend the ranks if you so choose by developing your website further.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Galleries With Hugo</title>
            <link>//localhost:1313/posts/galleries-with-hugo/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 15:42:54 -0500</pubDate>
            
            <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/galleries-with-hugo/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Definitely need to do this at some point in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;finally-i-find-an-excellent-easy-to-use-photo-gallery-viewer-with-hugo&#34;&gt;Finally I find an excellent, easy to use photo gallery viewer with Hugo&lt;/h1&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Definitely need to do this at some point in the future.</p>
<h1 id="finally-i-find-an-excellent-easy-to-use-photo-gallery-viewer-with-hugo">Finally I find an excellent, easy to use photo gallery viewer with Hugo</h1>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Tailcamera for any RC Aircraft</title>
            <link>//localhost:1313/posts/tailcamera-for-any-rc-aircraft/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2020 17:44:05 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/tailcamera-for-any-rc-aircraft/</guid>
            <description></description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Mostly Maine Trip Video</title>
            <link>//localhost:1313/posts/the-mostly-maine-trip-video/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 15:12:36 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/the-mostly-maine-trip-video/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enjoy this video, I&amp;rsquo;m really proud of how it turned out!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/RvZXMa7au5k?autoplay=1&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=1&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I finally convinced my best friend to lend me his drone after days of trying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I actually have a drone, an EMAX Tinyhawk 2, which &lt;strong&gt;note to self&lt;/strong&gt; I still need to fix. I crashed it pretty hard flying on the porch of my house against a metal support beam and one of the ESC&amp;rsquo;s is burned out.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>Enjoy this video, I&rsquo;m really proud of how it turned out!</strong></p>

    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/RvZXMa7au5k?autoplay=1&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=1&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"></iframe>
    </div>

<p>I finally convinced my best friend to lend me his drone after days of trying.</p>
<p>I actually have a drone, an EMAX Tinyhawk 2, which <strong>note to self</strong> I still need to fix. I crashed it pretty hard flying on the porch of my house against a metal support beam and one of the ESC&rsquo;s is burned out.</p>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/tinyhawkII.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<p>Enough about my drone. My friend lent me a DJI Mavic Air which is very different from my drone. My drone is meant for flying around and exploring. Crashing it is okay, and it doesn&rsquo;t record any video. The DJI Mavic Air, on the other hand, can record beautiful video at 4k 30fps. It&rsquo;s much larger and can fly for much longer, 15 mins vs 3 mins for my drone.</p>
<p>I just came back from a <a href="/gallery/maine-trip/">trip exploring New England</a>, and captured some astonishing footage with his drone. The DJI Mavic air is pictured in the thumbnail of this video.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>New Instagram Account</title>
            <link>//localhost:1313/posts/new-instagram-account/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 12:58:50 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/new-instagram-account/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I&amp;rsquo;ve posted anything on social media, with YouTube being the only exception. I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t even go as far as to call it social media. In fact, it&amp;rsquo;s almost been three years since I posted anything on my personal instagram account &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/nikolaiteslovich/&#34;&gt;@nikolaiteslovich&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I stopped. I guess it just happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These times are now gone, with the commencement of a new Instagram account: &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.instagram.com/projectniknek/&#34;&gt;@projectniknek&lt;/a&gt; which you should totally follow by the way. I created this to show the world what I&amp;rsquo;m doing with my time: hobbies and projects.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>It&rsquo;s been a while since I&rsquo;ve posted anything on social media, with YouTube being the only exception. I wouldn&rsquo;t even go as far as to call it social media. In fact, it&rsquo;s almost been three years since I posted anything on my personal instagram account <a href="https://www.instagram.com/nikolaiteslovich/">@nikolaiteslovich</a>.</p>
<p>I don&rsquo;t know why I stopped. I guess it just happened.</p>
<p>These times are now gone, with the commencement of a new Instagram account: <a href="https://www.instagram.com/projectniknek/">@projectniknek</a> which you should totally follow by the way. I created this to show the world what I&rsquo;m doing with my time: hobbies and projects.</p>
<p><strong>In my opinion, especially with the global pandemic that is going on, everyone is becoming more and more connected through the internet.</strong> It&rsquo;s becoming increasingly important, in my view, to become savvy on these social media platforms. It really doesn&rsquo;t take up any extra time, and I enjoy having my friends, and people who share my interests see what neat things I am doing with my time.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>A Tribute to National Parks</title>
            <link>//localhost:1313/posts/a-tribute-to-national-parks/</link>
            <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 12:09:18 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/a-tribute-to-national-parks/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Theodore Roosevelt once said,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;There is nothing so American as our national parks. The scenery and the wildlife are native. The fundamental idea behind the parks is native. It is, in brief, that the country belongs to the people, that it is in process of making for the enrichment of the lives of all of us. The parks stand as the outward symbol of the great human principle.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first national park—Yellowstone—was formed when president Ulysses S. Grant signed the landmark bill into law in 1875, nearly 150 years ago. Congress established Yellowstone National Park in the Territories of Montana and Wyoming &amp;ldquo;as a public park or pleasuring-ground for the benefit and enjoyment of the people&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Theodore Roosevelt once said,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>&ldquo;There is nothing so American as our national parks. The scenery and the wildlife are native. The fundamental idea behind the parks is native. It is, in brief, that the country belongs to the people, that it is in process of making for the enrichment of the lives of all of us. The parks stand as the outward symbol of the great human principle.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The first national park—Yellowstone—was formed when president Ulysses S. Grant signed the landmark bill into law in 1875, nearly 150 years ago. Congress established Yellowstone National Park in the Territories of Montana and Wyoming &ldquo;as a public park or pleasuring-ground for the benefit and enjoyment of the people&rdquo;</p>
<p>Congress placed this territory &ldquo;under exclusive control of the Secretary of the Interior.&rdquo; There is plenty of interesting history regarding national parks, however this speech is about the impact that they have directly on us and what they mean to me personally.</p>
<p>Last summer, I went on a road trip with my family across the country; from here in State College all the way to the North Western tip of Wyoming was over 2,000 miles of road. It took about 4 days one-way sitting in the car to arrive at our final destination: Yellowstone.</p>
<p>Don’t worry, though, those 4 days were completely worth it. Before I get into any stories, let me paint a picture for you of my typical vacation. A trip somewhere usually consists of hikes from sunrise to sunset with little time to spare.</p>
<p>When my family goes on vacation, I wouldn’t really call it a vacation, I would instead call it a workday. Although some prefer to actually rest and relax when they’re on vacation, my family prefers to be active—quite the opposite of relaxing.</p>
<p>I enjoy this up to a point, the point being where my legs hurt and I am ready to collapse on the trail and just take a nap. But I usually just keep going, inspired by the natural beauty around me with no time to think about the battery acid burning through my leg and back muscles.</p>
<p>I haul around a heavy camera everywhere I go on trips, the camera body, a Canon Digital SLR itself isn’t really that heavy. However the camera lens is a whole different story, it is a very heavy piece of glass. Some of the photos I took during this trip made it into this slideshow. Infact, this slideshow is almost purely made up of these photographs.</p>
<p>Like the intensity of my family’s vacations, the alarm clock blared into my ear as I lifted my heavy eyelids, my sister was still asleep. I looked out the window and noticed the sun peeking over the mountains, its majestic and warm rays just barely lighting and awakening the Yellowstone landscape from its somber.</p>
<p>Our parents agreed to rise early to evade the large crowds who would be bison roaming around the park, staying in large groups oftenly on tour busses hugging the road. I put on my hiking clothes, and woke up my sister by pulling back the blanket to expose her to the cold, fresh air of the wilderness.</p>
<p>We exited the shack we were staying in and drove out on the road. After what seemed like an eternity, we finally arrived at the trailhead of Fairy Falls Trail. We got out of the car only to be treated by the frigid, yet comforting breeze. We walked through the partially burned coniferous forest for a while.</p>
<p>It probably seemed longer than it actually was because I was still tired. As we were nearing the middle of the loop, a sharp smell overtook my nose. It smelled like rotten eggs. Then, I heard the sound of a small explosion. Above the treeline, I could see a column of water rise, like the most magnificent fountain.</p>
<p>Finally, we arrived at an opening between the trees and were greeted by something that seemed like it was not from this planet, maybe it should have been in Mars instead? It was a geyser in the middle of a small, geothermal lake. It was as colorful as a rainbow, covering the whole spectrum from dark blue to the bright orange.</p>
<p>Steam was steadily rising from the whole surface, and water would erupt out of the geyser every couple of minutes, easily reaching heights of the surrounding pine trees. A steaming, yellow river would flow from this lake, boiling everything alive in its path. I was no longer tired, but rather, stood excited and inspired.</p>
<p>Yellowstone was the first national park for a reason. The first people to set foot on that magical land noticed something unique. Everything from the pink sunrises to the magnificent orange-red sunsets. From the flaming hot, boiling, geothermal geysers to the bone-biting cold of the bare mountain peaks still covered in snow.</p>
<p>From the pine tree forests smelling of fresh sap, to the lifeless, silent forests that were scorched alive in a forest fire. From the comforting ground squirrels, to the vicious black bears. From the gentle wildflowers, to the fierce hawkmoths,. Everything about Yellowstone National Park was simply put: spectacular.</p>
<p>National parks are nature’s vital organs. Like the large intestine, they provide a safe home for native plants and animals. Like the kidneys and the liver, they clean air and water. Studies show that spending time in nature is good for your physical and mental health. Nature encourages physical activity, recreation and tranquility, and has even been shown to reduce depression. National parks give us places to enjoy and appreciate nature.</p>
<p>I want to thank all of the people who bought this land and converted it to a national park. I want to thank the people who understood and continue to understand the value in nature conservation. I also want to thank the rangers that take care of these parks to ensure they last for eternity and beyond.</p>
<p>Most importantly, I want to thank my parents for forcing me to go on hikes with them ever since I could remember, often against my will. Over time, they managed to successfully instill an appreciation for nature in me that I will carry with me as a part of me until I die and become one with nature.</p>
<p>As Transcendentalist Henry David Thoreau one wrote in his book Walden,</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“We need the tonic of wildness&hellip;At the same time that we are earnest to explore and learn all things, we require that all things be mysterious and unexplorable, that land and sea be indefinitely wild, unsurveyed and unfathomed by us because unfathomable. We can never have enough nature.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Thank you!</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>The Book of Bitcoin - An Analogy to Explain Bitcoin</title>
            <link>//localhost:1313/posts/the-book-of-bitcoin-an-analogy-to-explain-bitcoin/</link>
            <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 15:57:01 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/the-book-of-bitcoin-an-analogy-to-explain-bitcoin/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;This was a project for my speech and debate class, the sources are in the video&amp;rsquo;s description.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the video version of the speech:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/IN7gkAQoszo?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s the transcript of the speech:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-do-you-think-of-when-you-hear-the-word-bitcoin&#34;&gt;What do you think of when you hear the word “Bitcoin”?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;According to a 2017 YouGov survey, 62% of Americans believe that cryptocurrencies, like Bitcoin, are used for illegal purchases or don’t know what they’re used for at all.
Yet, all the cryptocurrencies combined are estimated to be worth about $230 billion. How much is that exactly? With that amount of money, the US Navy could buy about 20 of the latest Gerald R. Ford-class aircraft carriers.
$230 billion is about the whole GDP of Portugal. I have been interested in Cryptocurrencies ever since I started mining them with my computer at the start of this year.
Only recently, however, did I start to take them seriously through the preparation of this speech.
My name is Nikolai Nekrutenko and today I will attempt to explain what Bitcoin is along with the promise that it and other cryptocurrencies hold for the world’s future.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This was a project for my speech and debate class, the sources are in the video&rsquo;s description.</p>
<p><strong>Here&rsquo;s the video version of the speech:</strong></p>

    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/IN7gkAQoszo?autoplay=0&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=0&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"></iframe>
    </div>

<p><strong>Here&rsquo;s the transcript of the speech:</strong></p>
<h1 id="what-do-you-think-of-when-you-hear-the-word-bitcoin">What do you think of when you hear the word “Bitcoin”?</h1>
<p>According to a 2017 YouGov survey, 62% of Americans believe that cryptocurrencies, like Bitcoin, are used for illegal purchases or don’t know what they’re used for at all.
Yet, all the cryptocurrencies combined are estimated to be worth about $230 billion. How much is that exactly? With that amount of money, the US Navy could buy about 20 of the latest Gerald R. Ford-class aircraft carriers.
$230 billion is about the whole GDP of Portugal. I have been interested in Cryptocurrencies ever since I started mining them with my computer at the start of this year.
Only recently, however, did I start to take them seriously through the preparation of this speech.
My name is Nikolai Nekrutenko and today I will attempt to explain what Bitcoin is along with the promise that it and other cryptocurrencies hold for the world’s future.</p>
<h1 id="where-did-money-even-come-from">Where did money even come from?</h1>
<p>According to the book Sapiens by Yuval Noah Hararri, at the very beginning, there was no need for money. Hunters and gatherers shared goods and services through an economy of favors and obligations. For example, if you received a piece of meat from someone and you were known to be good at doctoring, they would expect free medical care.</p>
<p>With the rise of Kingdoms and Empires, the economy based around favors and obligations didn’t work when trying to trade between large numbers of strangers. Since they were strangers, how could they trust each other? What if they didn’t want the services or goods that you were offering? This is where the concept of money came in.</p>
<p>Although we think of it as coins and banknotes, money is simply anything that people are willing to use to represent the value of other things for exchanging goods and services. Everyone always wants money because everyone else also wants money. We accept the dollar as money because we trust the US secretary of the treasury in that the dollar will hold its value. Money allows us to convert, store, and transport wealth easily.</p>
<h1 id="so-what-even-is-bitcoin">So, what even is Bitcoin?</h1>
<p><strong>Bitcoin (shortened as BTC) is like a book.</strong> Transactions, the transfer of Bitcoin from one address to another are the lines in the book. Each page of the book can hold thousands of lines. Transactions do not become valid until a page with them is added to the book. Anyone can hold a copy of the book, and thousands of people do so already and are called nodes.</p>
<p>How do you add pages, or blocks, to the book? Once a page gets filled with lines, a special number, called the hash, is generated that depends on the transactions and the special number from the last page through an algorithm. Every line in the new page to be added is broadcasted to everyone who wants to contribute to the making of the book. Those people are called miners. In order to add a page to the book, you have to find the special number. When you find that special number, it is verified by the nodes. The only way to try and find this special number is to simply guess and then check. The algorithm also takes into account how fast the computers can find this special number and how many of them are online. It then changes its difficulty so that a page is added about every 10 minutes. The lucky miner who finds the correct special number gets a reward in the form of Bitcoin. The chance of you adding to the book depends on how powerful your computer is. Basically, everyone is guessing numbers as fast as they can until someone gets lucky. The guessing and checking is done on some form of a computer, so this reward incentivizes the book contributors to keep mining by typically covering their electrical costs.</p>
<p>After every chapter of the book is finished, the block reward, or the reward that comes from adding a page to the book, is halved. A new chapter is made every 210,000 pages, or about every four years. With the creation of bitcoin in 2008, this block reward used to be 50 BTC. Now, it is 6.25 BTC. These block rewards are the only way that new Bitcoin is put into circulation. When you perform a guess and check operation to try and find the special number, you currently have a 1 in 15 trillionth chance to guess correctly. It’s no longer profitable for everyday people like you and me to mine Bitcoin. Don’t worry. There are still plenty of other currencies to mine such as Ethereum or Ravencoin.</p>
<h1 id="cryptocurrencies-offer-several-advantages-over-conventional-money">Cryptocurrencies offer several advantages over conventional money.</h1>
<p>First, they diversify your portfolio. Governments tend to just print money when it is needed, often neglecting the risks of doing so and greatly impacting the economy. In Venezuela, CNBC reported that the overall inflation rate has recently reached over 10 million percent. We tend to think that our governments are stable, which is why we trust the dollar. But what happens if the government suddenly collapses, or loses its grip on reality? All those dollars would be completely useless. This is where the promise of cryptocurrencies such as Bitcoin come in. By their very nature, they are decentralized which makes them immune to government manipulation. Second, Bitcoin has a finite supply at 21 million BTC; you can’t just make more Bitcoins because of the block reward halving. Third, the blockchain, or the book, is always available to the public. This makes Bitcoin an anonymous yet transparent network in the sense that anyone can see the transactions, but cannot actually link the addresses to anyone’s identity. Thousands of nodes have a copy of the book, and since new pages depend on previous pages, it is resistant to hacking.</p>
<p>Another pro, or a con, depending on who you ask, is that Bitcoin can have any price, but no real value, since it isn’t backed by any physical asset. This makes Bitcoin extremely volatile. A problem with Bitcoin is that it is slow at handling transactions, about 7 transactions/sec compared to a maximum of 24,000 for VISA according to several sources. Another issue with Bitcoin is that it uses a lot of power, we’re talking as much as the eBay, Facebook, and Google servers combined. Since Bitcoin was the first cryptocurrency among thousands, newer ones address these problems.</p>
<h1 id="cryptocurrencies-can-bring-more-transparency-and-accountability-to-the-world">Cryptocurrencies can bring more transparency and accountability to the world.</h1>
<p>They hold a lot of potential in the future and there is no doubt that they will soon overtake the current economic system. That is, only if they are designed well. The anonymous founder of bitcoin, Satoshi Nakamoto once said:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>“If you don’t believe it or don’t get it, I don’t have the time to try to convince you, sorry.”</p>
</blockquote>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>EOLRC - Build Guide</title>
            <link>//localhost:1313/posts/eolrc-build-guide/</link>
            <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 10:30:15 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/eolrc-build-guide/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Note that this is not a build guide of the car itself. Rather, how to integrate the 3D printed parts with the plane parts for your own projects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;printing-the-parts&#34;&gt;Printing the parts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The parts can be found in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/NikolaiTeslovich/plans/tree/master/EOLRC&#34;&gt;plans GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend printing the All_parts_arranged.stl&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used an Ultimaker 3 to print the parts with eSun PLA+ at a 0.2mm layer height at 215C, 35% infill, along with a PETG brim for easy cleanup. They were printed relatively slow at 60mm/s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Note that this is not a build guide of the car itself. Rather, how to integrate the 3D printed parts with the plane parts for your own projects.</p>
<h1 id="printing-the-parts">Printing the parts</h1>
<p><strong>The parts can be found in the <a href="https://github.com/NikolaiTeslovich/plans/tree/master/EOLRC">plans GitHub repo</a>.</strong></p>
<p>I recommend printing the All_parts_arranged.stl</p>
<p>I used an Ultimaker 3 to print the parts with eSun PLA+ at a 0.2mm layer height at 215C, 35% infill, along with a PETG brim for easy cleanup. They were printed relatively slow at 60mm/s.</p>
<p>The print took about an hour and a half and used under 20 grams of filament.</p>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC1.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h1 id="bill-of-parts">Bill of parts</h1>
<ul>
<li><strong>Part (what I used)</strong></li>
<li>Battery (3S1P 2200mAh LiPo)</li>
<li>Electronic speed controller (BLHeli 20A brushless)</li>
<li>Motor with a 16mm by 19mm mounting screw arrangement (Flite Test Radial 2212-1050kV)</li>
<li>Radio receiver (FrSky X4R)</li>
<li>9g servo (some cheap one off Amazon)</li>
<li>All in one FPV camera (AKK 40CH 5.8G 0/25/50/200mW Switchable Micro AIO FPV Camera)</li>
<li>3D printed parts</li>
<li>Screws (All of these come with the servo and motor)
<ul>
<li>4x cone-shaped motor screws</li>
<li>2x long servo screws</li>
<li>1x short servo screw</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC2.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h1 id="bill-of-tools">Bill of tools</h1>
<ul>
<li>Adjustable wrench</li>
<li>Phillips No. 1 screwdriver</li>
<li>Radio control transmitter/remote</li>
<li>FPV goggles with a 5.8GHz system</li>
</ul>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC3.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h1 id="lets-put-the-parts-together-damn-it">Let&rsquo;s put the parts together damn it!</h1>
<h2 id="step-1---binding-the-receiver">Step 1 - Binding the receiver</h2>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC4.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<p>Make a new model with zero trims. Check with your manufacturer&rsquo;s instructions on binding the radio with the receiver.</p>
<p>We&rsquo;ll need this for a later step.</p>
<h2 id="step-2---attaching-the-motor-to-axle-adapter-to-the-motor">Step 2 - Attaching the motor to axle adapter to the motor</h2>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC5.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h3 id="partstools">Parts/Tools</h3>
<ul>
<li>Motor with a 16mm by 19mm mounting arrangement</li>
<li>Motor to axle adapter</li>
<li>Adjustable wrench</li>
</ul>
<p>You can use additional tools for this, but be careful to <em><strong>not</strong></em> <strong>misshape the motor bell</strong>. I totally haven&rsquo;t done that before.</p>
<h3 id="steps">Steps</h3>
<ol>
<li>Screw on the motor to axle adapter onto the motor while making sure that it is screwed all the way down.</li>
</ol>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC6.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h2 id="step-3---affixing-the-motor-to-the-motor-mount">Step 3 - Affixing the motor to the motor mount</h2>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC7.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h3 id="partstools-1">Parts/Tools</h3>
<ul>
<li>Motor from step 2</li>
<li>Motor mount</li>
<li>4x cone-shaped motor screws</li>
<li>Philips No. 1 screwdriver</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="steps-1">Steps</h3>
<ol>
<li>Attach the motor to the motor mount using the screws</li>
</ol>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC8.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h2 id="step-4---mounting-the-servo-to-the-servo-holder">Step 4 - Mounting the servo to the servo holder</h2>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC9.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h3 id="partstools-2">Parts/Tools</h3>
<ul>
<li>9g servo</li>
<li>Servo mount</li>
<li>2x long servo screws</li>
<li>Philips No. 1 screwdriver</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="steps-2">Steps</h3>
<ol>
<li>Push the servo into the mount until it is flush</li>
<li>Screw in the screws to secure the Servo</li>
</ol>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC10.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h2 id="step-5---securing-the-servo-arm-to-the-servo">Step 5 - Securing the servo arm to the servo</h2>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC11.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h3 id="partstools-3">Parts/Tools</h3>
<ul>
<li>Radio receiver</li>
<li>Battery</li>
<li>Electronic speed controller</li>
<li>Servo assembly from step 4</li>
<li>Servo arm</li>
<li>1x short servo screw</li>
<li>Philips No. 1 screwdriver</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="steps-3">Steps</h3>
<ol>
<li>Plug the battery into the electronic speed controller</li>
<li>Power on the radio receiver using the electronic speed controller</li>
<li>Plug the servo wire into the second channel of the speed controller</li>
<li>Turn on the radio controller, it should connect to the radio receiver</li>
<li>Test that the servo works by moving the sticks on the controller</li>
<li>While leaving the sticks of the radio centered, line up the servo arm parallel to the long side of the servo mount and screw it in. (This is so that the servo arm is centered)</li>
</ol>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC12.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h2 id="step-6---fixing-the-aio-fpv-camera-to-the-camera-mount">Step 6 - Fixing the AIO FPV camera to the camera mount</h2>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC13.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h3 id="partstools-4">Parts/Tools</h3>
<ul>
<li>AIO FPV camera</li>
<li>Camera mount</li>
<li>Hot glue (optional)</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="steps-4">Steps</h3>
<ol>
<li>(Optional) Put hot glue inside the camera mount. This will secure the camera much more than just pushing it in and having it stay attached due to friction.</li>
<li>Carefully yet forcefully push the camera into the Camera mount. The camera lens should be flush with the exterior of the mount.</li>
</ol>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/EOLRC14.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h1 id="making-sure-that-the-whole-system-works">Making sure that the whole system works</h1>
<p>These gifs were recorded through the FPV camera, so at least I know that that works.</p>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/controller.gif"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<p>With everything properly wired up, it was time to test all the parts.</p>
<ul>
<li>The three motor cables were joined with the ones coming out of the electronic speed controller (ESC)</li>
<li>The ESC cable was plugged into the first channel of the receiver</li>
<li>The FPV camera was plugged into 5V BEC output of the ESC, for which I made a custom splitter</li>
<li>The servo cable was plugged into the second channel of the receiver</li>
<li>Obviously the battery was plugged into the ESC</li>
</ul>
<p>When I moved the left stick of the controller vertically, the motor span up. When I moved the right stick on the controller horizontally, the servo turned.</p>
<p><strong>If you want to reverse the motor direction, just swap any two of the three motor wires</strong></p>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/EOLRC_build/servomotor.gif"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h1 id="what-next">What next?</h1>
<p><strong>Congratulations, you&rsquo;re finally done. Now give yourself a big pat on the back</strong></p>
<blockquote>
<p>Let your imagination run wild! As they say: the sky is the limit!</p>
</blockquote>
<p><a href="/posts/eolrc-an-extremely-overkill-lego-rc-car-from-plane-parts/">Here&rsquo;s what I built using these parts.</a></p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>EOLRC - An Extremely Overkill LEGO RC Car (from Plane Parts)</title>
            <link>//localhost:1313/posts/eolrc-an-extremely-overkill-lego-rc-car-from-plane-parts/</link>
            <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 07:27:42 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/eolrc-an-extremely-overkill-lego-rc-car-from-plane-parts/</guid>
            <description>&lt;div style=&#34;position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
      &lt;iframe allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share&#34; allowfullscreen=&#34;allowfullscreen&#34; loading=&#34;eager&#34; referrerpolicy=&#34;strict-origin-when-cross-origin&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/VaGnldsxeiA?autoplay=1&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=1&amp;amp;start=0&#34; style=&#34;position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;&#34; title=&#34;YouTube video&#34;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;its-been-a-while&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s been a while&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;since I last played around with LEGO Technic. About 4 years to be exact. I can say with absolute confidence that this was my favorite way to spend time in my
younger years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recollect building all sorts of crazy things from an automatic crossbow to a massive Mercedes Benz Unimog with a functioning suspension and a pneumatic crane. Over the years, I have acquired an impressive amount of LEGO technic parts that are still scattered everywhere around the house.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[
    <div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
      <iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/VaGnldsxeiA?autoplay=1&amp;controls=1&amp;end=0&amp;loop=0&amp;mute=1&amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"></iframe>
    </div>

<h2 id="its-been-a-while">It&rsquo;s been a while</h2>
<p>since I last played around with LEGO Technic. About 4 years to be exact. I can say with absolute confidence that this was my favorite way to spend time in my
younger years.</p>
<p>I recollect building all sorts of crazy things from an automatic crossbow to a massive Mercedes Benz Unimog with a functioning suspension and a pneumatic crane. Over the years, I have acquired an impressive amount of LEGO technic parts that are still scattered everywhere around the house.</p>
<h2 id="i-recently-had-to-decommission">I recently had to decommission</h2>
<p>one of my favorite birds of all time. It was a <a href="https://www.flitetest.com/articles/ft-versa-wing">FT(Flite Test) Versa wing</a> with the <a href="https://www.flitetest.com/articles/blunt-nose-conversion-ft-versa-build">Blunt Nose modification</a>. It had to be put out of service due to a combination of old age and abuse like trying to hit a small gap between the trees.</p>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/versa1.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<p>This gave me several spare electronic components including a 20A BLHeli brushless ESC(electronic speed controller), a radio receiver, a Flite Test Radial 2212-1050kV motor, and an AIO(all in one) FPV camera.</p>
<h2 id="i-hopped-onto-fusion-360">I hopped onto Fusion 360</h2>
<p>and started modeling adapters to those electronic components so that they could be compatible with LEGO Technic. I&rsquo;ll be honest, it took multiple iterations to design parts that interfaced well with the plane and LEGO parts.</p>
<p>In the end, I designed and printed four parts: a servo holder so that the RC car could steer, a motor to lego axle adapter, a FPV camera holder, and last but not least a motor mount. Later on, I also designed an arm from the servo to the lego steering mechanism, but this is not in the pictures shown below.</p>
<p><strong>A build guide will also be written soon, so stay posted.</strong> <em><strong>Update</strong></em> <a href="/posts/eolrc-build-guide/">It&rsquo;s already written.</a></p>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/rclego1.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>



    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/rclego2.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h2 id="here-is-the-final-result">Here is the final result:</h2>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/rclego3.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>



    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/rclego4.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h2 id="i-have-to-say">I have to say</h2>
<p>I am very impressed with the performance of this car. It has enough torque to just about climb over anything and on a 3S 2200mAh LiPo, the battery lasts for ages, about 1.5 hrs of regular use.</p>
<p>However, LEGO Technic clearly isn&rsquo;t designed for this. For instance, the lego axles heated up so much that they fused the gears onto them permanently. I sprayed the moving parts with WD-40, but that didn&rsquo;t seem to help too much.</p>
<p>I also did some water testing, and it seems to be surprisingly waterproof. <strong>Please don&rsquo;t abuse your electronics.</strong> I did it so that you wouldn&rsquo;t have to.</p>
<h2 id="what-are-its-features">What are its features?</h2>
<ul>
<li>A fully functioning differential</li>
<li>Optional 5mm led lights</li>
<li>FPV</li>
<li>Hella battery life</li>
<li>Quick and easy to build and repair after a crash</li>
<li>Customizability that comes with LEGO</li>
<li>Probably cheaper than buying the LEGO electronics</li>
<li>Extremely overpowered</li>
<li>Surprisingly waterproof</li>
<li>Extremely unstable</li>
<li>Brings back childhood nostalgia</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>Let&#39;s Kill This MacBook! - How to Mine Monero on a Mac</title>
            <link>//localhost:1313/posts/lets-kill-this-macbook-how-to-mine-monero-on-a-mac/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 10:04:55 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/lets-kill-this-macbook-how-to-mine-monero-on-a-mac/</guid>
            <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;center&#34; &gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;//localhost:1313/img/skylerdontlikemacs.png&#34;  alt=&#34;Hello Friend&#34;   style=&#34;border-radius: 8px;&#34;  /&gt;

        
    &lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;h1 id=&#34;my-friends-mac-is-nearing-its-end&#34;&gt;My friend&amp;rsquo;s Mac is nearing its end&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He&amp;rsquo;s already had it, the one in the picture above, for a couple of years, and the battery is starting to degrade among several other serious issues. Since it is nearing its end soon, in the time that it isn&amp;rsquo;t being used it could mine some cryptocurrency.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;MacBooks are known for their subpar cooling systems as demonstrated in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MlOPPuNv4Ec&#34;&gt;this video&lt;/a&gt;. We are going to set up this mac for mining &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.getmonero.org/&#34;&gt;Monero(XMR)&lt;/a&gt;, a type of cryptocurrency that can be mined with a CPU. He is only going to earn a couple pennies per day, but it&amp;rsquo;s better than nothing. I don&amp;rsquo;t know how he&amp;rsquo;ll be able to sleep through the insane fan noise. Maybe he&amp;rsquo;ll have to run an extension cable to his closet.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[
    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/skylerdontlikemacs.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h1 id="my-friends-mac-is-nearing-its-end">My friend&rsquo;s Mac is nearing its end</h1>
<p>He&rsquo;s already had it, the one in the picture above, for a couple of years, and the battery is starting to degrade among several other serious issues. Since it is nearing its end soon, in the time that it isn&rsquo;t being used it could mine some cryptocurrency.</p>
<p>MacBooks are known for their subpar cooling systems as demonstrated in <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MlOPPuNv4Ec">this video</a>. We are going to set up this mac for mining <a href="https://www.getmonero.org/">Monero(XMR)</a>, a type of cryptocurrency that can be mined with a CPU. He is only going to earn a couple pennies per day, but it&rsquo;s better than nothing. I don&rsquo;t know how he&rsquo;ll be able to sleep through the insane fan noise. Maybe he&rsquo;ll have to run an extension cable to his closet.</p>

    <figure class="center" >
        <img src="/img/monero.png"  alt="Hello Friend"   style="border-radius: 8px;"  />

        
    </figure>


<h1 id="disclaimer">Disclaimer</h1>
<p>You have been warned that there are risks such as damage to the computer keeping it at a high temperature for long periods of time.</p>
<p>It is barely profitable to do this on a laptop.</p>
<p>Pools usually have a minimum of 0.1 XMR payout, so it would take at least a couple of months to be able to withdraw the Monero if using a laptop.</p>
<p>Please do this at your own risk.</p>
<h1 id="installing-xmrig">Installing xmrig</h1>
<p><em><strong>Open the terminal application on your mac and copy and paste the code below into it, step by step.</strong></em></p>
<p>Install Homebrew, a package manager for macOS:</p>
<p><code>/bin/bash -c &quot;$(curl -fsSL https://raw.githubusercontent.com/Homebrew/install/master/install.sh)&quot;</code></p>
<p>Install the required dependencies with Homebrew:</p>
<p><code>brew install git cmake libuv libmicrohttpd openssl hwloc</code></p>
<p>Clone, or in other words, save the xmrig mining software to your computer with git:</p>
<p><code>git clone https://github.com/xmrig/xmrig.git</code></p>
<p>Make the build directory inside of the xmrig directory:</p>
<p><code>mkdir xmrig/build</code></p>
<p>Navigate into the build directory inside xmrig:</p>
<p><code>cd xmrig/build</code></p>
<p>Build the program with cmake, then make:</p>
<p><code>cmake .. -DOPENSSL_ROOT_DIR=/usr/local/opt/openssl</code></p>
<p><code>make -j$(sysctl -n hw.logicalcpu)</code></p>
<h1 id="generating-the-xmrig-config-code">Generating the xmrig config code</h1>
<p>The people over at xmrig made a fantastic configuration wizard which helps create a line of code to start the miner.</p>
<p>Open the <a href="https://xmrig.com/wizard">xmrig configuration wizard</a></p>
<p>Click the <strong>New configuration</strong> button.</p>
<p>Press on the <strong>Add pool</strong> button.</p>
<p>Click on your pool of choice in the dropdown. I use the supporxmr.com pool.</p>
<p>Then there will be a pop-up where it asks for the <strong>Monero wallet address</strong>, where you type in your wallet. You can also choose to set a <strong>Worker name</strong>, something like MacBookPro13.</p>
<p>Navigate to the <strong>Backends</strong> tab and only turn on the <strong>CPU</strong> option. You can use a GPU if you have one, but I don&rsquo;t recommend it as there are far more profitable currencies to mine with a GPU.</p>
<p>Next, select the <strong>Misc</strong> tab and set a donation percentage, I chose to leave the <strong>HTTP API</strong> option off.</p>
<p>Finally, navigate to the <strong>Result</strong> tab, click on macOS option under the <strong>Command line</strong>. Copy the line of code.</p>
<h1 id="making-an-executable-shell-script">Making an executable shell script</h1>
<p>While this is not a required step, I recommend that you do it for ease of use.</p>
<p>Go back to the terminal app.</p>
<p>If it is still open, navigate to the user(<strong>~</strong>) directory:</p>
<p><code>cd .. &amp;&amp; cd ..</code></p>
<p>If you reopened it, double check that you are in the <strong>~</strong> directory.</p>
<p>Create a shell script called xmr:</p>
<p><code>touch xmr.sh</code></p>
<p>Make it executable:</p>
<p><code>chmod +x xmr.sh</code></p>
<p>Edit the shell script to make it navigate to the xmrig/build directory, and start the miner from there:</p>
<p><code>nano xmr.sh</code></p>
<p>A basic text editor will show up.</p>
<p>Type the following into it, each on a separate line:</p>
<p><code>cd xmrig/build</code></p>
<p><code>copy and paste the code that we generated earlier from the configurator</code></p>
<p>Press control x, and then press y followed by enter to save the edits made to the file.</p>
<h1 id="running-the-shell-script">Running the shell script</h1>
<p>It&rsquo;s actually really easy, type the following into terminal from the <strong>~</strong> directory, which is the default when you open Terminal:</p>
<p><code>./xmr.sh</code></p>
<p>To stop the program press control c.</p>
<p>You can monitor all sorts of statistics on the pool&rsquo;s home page, logging in with your wallet address.</p>
<h1 id="updating-xmrig">Updating xmrig</h1>
<p>Navigate to the build directory:</p>
<p><code>cd xmrig/build</code></p>
<p>Update using the git pull command:</p>
<p><code>git pull</code></p>
<h1 id="resources">Resources</h1>
<ul>
<li>
<p>Based around the <a href="https://xmrig.com/docs/miner/macos-build">official xmrig macOS build guide</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://coin360.com/coin/monero-xmr">Monero(XMR) price chart</a></p>
</li>
<li>
<p><a href="https://www.getmonero.org/">Monero&rsquo;s official website</a></p>
</li>
</ul>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
        <item>
            <title>My First Post</title>
            <link>//localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</link>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 15:21:48 -0400</pubDate>
            
            <guid>//localhost:1313/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello World!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-did-i-make-this-website-and-what-even-is-it&#34;&gt;Why did I make this website and what even is it?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m glad you asked although you probably didn&amp;rsquo;t! I made and &lt;strong&gt;will continue&lt;/strong&gt; to make this website because I want to learn how to build a website. I also enjoy writing, especially when it isn&amp;rsquo;t tied to a grade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I will be posting about everything from a small cryptocurrency mining operation that I run in the basement to my favorite hobby of RC flight to my own ice cream recipes and everything in between. In short, the things that I do to keep myself sane, especially during quarantine. I&amp;rsquo;ll post at least every week. This is my blog site.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
            <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hello World!</p>
<h2 id="why-did-i-make-this-website-and-what-even-is-it">Why did I make this website and what even is it?</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;m glad you asked although you probably didn&rsquo;t! I made and <strong>will continue</strong> to make this website because I want to learn how to build a website. I also enjoy writing, especially when it isn&rsquo;t tied to a grade.</p>
<p>I will be posting about everything from a small cryptocurrency mining operation that I run in the basement to my favorite hobby of RC flight to my own ice cream recipes and everything in between. In short, the things that I do to keep myself sane, especially during quarantine. I&rsquo;ll post at least every week. This is my blog site.</p>
]]></content>
        </item>
        
    </channel>
</rss>
