<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nikolai Nekrutenko</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nikolai Nekrutenko</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 23:37:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Adirondacks Adventures</title>
      <link>/gallery/adirondacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 23:37:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gallery/adirondacks/</guid>
      <description>Went up to the Adirondacks with the girlfriend for the labor day long weekend. It&amp;rsquo;s only 2 weeks into the semester and I definitely needed this break.&#xA;The hike we went on was called Hurricane mountain and it was absolutely beautiful, definitely recommend it, especially the sketchy firetower up top that clearly is in need of some Loctite.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2023 21:26:54 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Columbia Icefield, Jasper National Park&#xA;Hi, nice to meet you! I&amp;rsquo;m Nikolai! I am a tinker and a doer. I thrive by working on complex and open-ended projects that challenge me.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m looking for an internship for the summer of 2024 that is applied physics and engineering-related, specifically something Research and Development oriented!&#xA;I am a junior majoring in Physics with a concentration in Electrical Engineering at Cornell University. I plan to pursue a M.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to Build a Website: A Guide for Command-Line Novices</title>
      <link>/posts/how-to-build-a-website-a-guide-for-command-line-novices/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Jun 2021 10:38:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/how-to-build-a-website-a-guide-for-command-line-novices/</guid>
      <description>Formerly titled: How to Build a Website for Your Studio (or Anything): A Step by Step Guide&#xA;Introduction This guide is intended for Macintosh users who have never programmed before. With a bit of searching, the same steps can easily be applied to Windows and Linux machines.&#xA;Most will agree that a book is judged by its cover—for better or worse. Websites are the covers of your studio, organization, or even yourself, which are the books.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ice Storm Pt. 2</title>
      <link>/gallery/ice-storm-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Feb 2021 13:20:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gallery/ice-storm-2/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve had enough sitting at home, not leaving my neighborhood for a week. So, I ventured out to Jo Hays Vista with my newly built FPV freestyle drone and camera at my side.&#xA;Unfortunately I forgot to charge the FPV goggles before hand, so the drone was practically useless. I&amp;rsquo;m still glad I saw the harsh, wind-chiseled ice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ice Storm</title>
      <link>/gallery/ice-storm/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 09:15:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gallery/ice-storm/</guid>
      <description>A massive ice storm just passed by State College. So while most people were scared of slipping and breaking an arm, I decided to venture out into the neighborhood and nearby golf course with my macro 35mm lens.&#xA;I find the texture of the ice fascinating—it resembles a network of plant cells, or looks like some carbonated drink.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phone Flashlight Photography</title>
      <link>/gallery/light-drawings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 16:07:27 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gallery/light-drawings/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I did something overly creative, like drawing circles with fire. So, here&amp;rsquo;s a remedy to that!&#xA;These were made by leaving the shutter open for a few seconds (30) and using my phone&amp;rsquo;s flashlight to draw while the sensor gathered light.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stonevalley</title>
      <link>/gallery/stonevalley/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 22:25:09 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>/gallery/stonevalley/</guid>
      <description>Explored the areas around the frozen Lake Perez—where I used to sail in the summer—one of my favorite places of all time.&#xA;I also attempted the tilt-shift effect in Photoshop from a nearby overlook of State College. I think the house turned out the best!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snow</title>
      <link>/gallery/snow/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 10:45:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gallery/snow/</guid>
      <description>Happy New Year!&#xA;A major snowstorm recently unleashed its wrath on us, for a grand total of 14in or 35cm of fluffy, dry snow!&#xA;Here are some of my favorite long exposures from the evening.&#xA;Yes, you did notice something slightly different about this gallery. Actually, I probably already converted all of my existing galleries by now, so whatever.&#xA;I&amp;rsquo;m using a new system to generate these galleries. No longer do I have to deal with endless markdown tables!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snow - Aftermath</title>
      <link>/gallery/snow-aftermath/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jan 2021 10:45:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gallery/snow-aftermath/</guid>
      <description>It was one of those fictional, silent winter mornings&#xA;14in or 35cm of fluffy, dry snow had just finished precipitating</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 16:26:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>Nikolai Nekrutenko nan34@cornell.edu · https://github.com/NikolaiTeslovich · State College, PA 16803 Education Cornell University, Physics Major &amp;amp; CS Minor in the College of Arts and Sciences&#xA;September 2021 - May 2025&#xA;Semester 1 AEP 1200 - Intro to Nanoscience and Nanoengineering MATH 1920 - Multivariable Calculus for Engineers PHYS 1116 - Physics I: Mechanics and Special Relativity Semester 2 (in progress) CS 1110 - Intro to Computing with Python MATH 2930 - Differential Equations for Engineers PHYS 2217 - Physics II: Electricity and Magnetism Pennsylvania State University, Non-matriculated Student</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nikolai Nekrutenko&#39;s OLD Resume</title>
      <link>/resume_old/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Sep 2020 16:26:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/resume_old/</guid>
      <description>nekrutnikolai@gmail.com · https://nnekrut.netlify.app/ · https://github.com/NikolaiTeslovich&#xA;I highly recommend viewing this document online: https://nnekrut.netlify.app/cv/&#xA;Education Cornell University&#xA;September 2021 - May 2025&#xA;College of Arts &amp;amp; Sciences Majoring in Physics Minoring in Computer Science Pennsylvania State University&#xA;January 2021 - May 2021&#xA;4.0 GPA&#xA;Took three courses as a non-matriculated student for a total of 10 credits&#xA;MATH 141 (Calculus with Analytical Geometry II) CHEM 112 (Chemical Principles II) CHEM 110 (Chemical Principles I) State College Area High School</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flying RC Jets!</title>
      <link>/gallery/rcplanes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 15:50:00 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gallery/rcplanes/</guid>
      <description>Here are some pictures of my friends over at @teamsketchyfpv flying some of their planes.&#xA;Thanks to them for inviting me, I had an absolute blast.&#xA;Looks like it&amp;rsquo;s time for me to get an RC jet!&#xA;And yes, we did keep at least six feet apart.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mostly Maine Trip Video</title>
      <link>/posts/the-mostly-maine-trip-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 15:12:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-mostly-maine-trip-video/</guid>
      <description>Enjoy this video, I&amp;rsquo;m really proud of how it turned out!&#xA;I finally convinced my best friend to lend me his drone after days of trying.&#xA;I actually have a drone, an EMAX Tinyhawk 2, which note to self I still need to fix. I crashed it pretty hard flying on the porch of my house against a metal support beam and one of the ESC&amp;rsquo;s is burned out.&#xA;Enough about my drone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Mostly Maine Trip</title>
      <link>/gallery/maine-trip/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 15:01:19 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gallery/maine-trip/</guid>
      <description>I recently went on a camping/cabining trip with my family around New England, especially Maine.&#xA;I know there are a lot of photographs, but I really like all of these.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Book of Bitcoin - An Analogy to Explain Bitcoin</title>
      <link>/posts/the-book-of-bitcoin-an-analogy-to-explain-bitcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 15:57:01 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-book-of-bitcoin-an-analogy-to-explain-bitcoin/</guid>
      <description>This was a project for my speech and debate class, the sources are in the video&amp;rsquo;s description.&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s the video version of the speech:&#xA;Here&amp;rsquo;s the transcript of the speech:&#xA;What do you think of when you hear the word “Bitcoin”? According to a 2017 YouGov survey, 62% of Americans believe that cryptocurrencies, like Bitcoin, are used for illegal purchases or don’t know what they’re used for at all. Yet, all the cryptocurrencies combined are estimated to be worth about $230 billion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EOLRC - Build Guide</title>
      <link>/posts/eolrc-build-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 10:30:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/eolrc-build-guide/</guid>
      <description>Note that this is not a build guide of the car itself. Rather, how to integrate the 3D printed parts with the plane parts for your own projects.&#xA;Printing the parts The parts can be found in the plans GitHub repo.&#xA;I recommend printing the All_parts_arranged.stl&#xA;I used an Ultimaker 3 to print the parts with eSun PLA+ at a 0.2mm layer height at 215C, 35% infill, along with a PETG brim for easy cleanup.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Around the Garden</title>
      <link>/gallery/garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 20:51:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gallery/garden/</guid>
      <description>I walked around the garden and garage to see what pictures I could take. Here are the ones that I liked:&#xA;The thumbnails are significantly darker than the images themselves because I used the wrong color profile. &amp;#x1f622;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacuum Tube Amplifier</title>
      <link>/gallery/vaccumtubes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 18:09:23 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gallery/vaccumtubes/</guid>
      <description>Last night, I was listening to music on a vacuum tube amplifier that I assembled a while back from a kit.&#xA;I really liked the look of the tubes in dark, they had a very retro aesthetic. Since they glowed in a very gentle orange-red color, they were perfect for a long exposure.&#xA;Maybe it has to do with the look of these tubes, but I&amp;rsquo;m convinced that music sounds better on tubes than on a transistor amp.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Water Lilies &amp; Dragonflies</title>
      <link>/gallery/waterlilies-dragonflies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 16:51:17 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gallery/waterlilies-dragonflies/</guid>
      <description>Today, I headed down to The Arboretum at Penn State to see what flowers and insects were in store for me.&#xA;At first, I decided to bring a 35mm macro lens. However, after seeing all of the dragonflies and lilies, I biked home in record time and snagged a telephoto lens.&#xA;I present to you the Water lilies and Dragonflies at The Arboretum at Penn State.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EOLRC - An Extremely Overkill LEGO RC Car (from Plane Parts)</title>
      <link>/posts/eolrc-an-extremely-overkill-lego-rc-car-from-plane-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 07:27:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/eolrc-an-extremely-overkill-lego-rc-car-from-plane-parts/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last played around with LEGO Technic. About 4 years to be exact. I can say with absolute confidence that this was my favorite way to spend time in my younger years.&#xA;I recollect building all sorts of crazy things from an automatic crossbow to a massive Mercedes Benz Unimog with a functioning suspension and a pneumatic crane. Over the years, I have acquired an impressive amount of LEGO technic parts that are still scattered everywhere around the house.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Solstice Fun</title>
      <link>/gallery/solstice-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 10:45:11 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/gallery/solstice-fun/</guid>
      <description>I went camping with my family in the beautiful Northern PA countryside, near the finger lakes.&#xA;To celebrate the longest day of the year, I found a stick about my height and lit both ends of it on fire. It was similar to the staff that I use in Tang Soo Do, so I messed around with various techniques. Particularly, I really enjoy doing the figure-eight technique where you essentially spin the stick in the shape of an infinity sign.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Kill This MacBook! - How to Mine Monero on a Mac</title>
      <link>/posts/lets-kill-this-macbook-how-to-mine-monero-on-a-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 10:04:55 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/lets-kill-this-macbook-how-to-mine-monero-on-a-mac/</guid>
      <description>My friend&amp;rsquo;s Mac is nearing its end He&amp;rsquo;s already had it, the one in the picture above, for a couple of years, and the battery is starting to degrade among several other serious issues. Since it is nearing its end soon, in the time that it isn&amp;rsquo;t being used it could mine some cryptocurrency.&#xA;MacBooks are known for their subpar cooling systems as demonstrated in this video. We are going to set up this mac for mining Monero(XMR), a type of cryptocurrency that can be mined with a CPU.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 15:21:48 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hello World!&#xA;Why did I make this website and what even is it? I&amp;rsquo;m glad you asked although you probably didn&amp;rsquo;t! I made and will continue to make this website because I want to learn how to build a website. I also enjoy writing, especially when it isn&amp;rsquo;t tied to a grade.&#xA;I will be posting about everything from a small cryptocurrency mining operation that I run in the basement to my favorite hobby of RC flight to my own ice cream recipes and everything in between.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/collegeapps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/collegeapps/</guid>
      <description>Note: this article is still in progress&#xA;Applying to colleges is a daunting and uniformed process. So, in an effort to make the process more transparent, I&amp;rsquo;ll share everything about my process, my essays, my high school extracurricular activities, and much more.&#xA;First of all Here are the statistics on where I applied to, where I got in, and where I actually decided to go:&#xA;In total, I applied to about 15 places.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/websites/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/websites/</guid>
      <description>I want you to have a website So far, I have built documentation websites, organization websites, and personal websites integrated with a photo gallery.&#xA;What makes these websites special Astonishing on both desktop and mobile Secure, fast, and SEO-ready Google Analytics and Search Console supported Infinitely customizable Photo gallery support with hugo-shortcode-gallery Favicon support Deployable on Netlify If you would like a website Pick a Hugo theme Test it on both mobile and desktop to make sure that you like it Please send me an email at nekrutnikolai@gmail.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
