<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nikolai Nekrutenko</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nikolai Nekrutenko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 10:45:11 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Solstice Fun</title>
      <link>/gallery/solstice-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 10:45:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/gallery/solstice-fun/</guid>
      <description>I went camping with my family in the beautiful Northern PA countryside, near the finger lakes.
To celebrate the longest day of the year, I found a stick about my height and lit both ends of it on fire. It was similar to the staff that I use in Tang Soo Do, so I messed around with various techniques. Particularly, I really enjoy doing the figure-eight technique where you essentially spin the stick in the shape of an infinity sign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nikolai&#39;s Mowing</title>
      <link>/mowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 15:26:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/mowing/</guid>
      <description>Why am I doing this? Strangely enough, I enjoy lawn mowing and find it to be an effective mind relaxant probably because I like enjoying the outdoors.
It&amp;rsquo;s the summer in the middle of the COVID-19 pandemic, and I want to earn some cash that I can use to fuel my hobbies and to start saving for the future.
Business model and info Customer satisfaction is at the core of Nikolai&amp;rsquo;s Mowing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Kill This MacBook! - How to Mine Monero on a Mac</title>
      <link>/posts/lets-kill-this-macbook-how-to-mine-monero-on-a-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 10:04:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lets-kill-this-macbook-how-to-mine-monero-on-a-mac/</guid>
      <description>MacBook Pro 13 without TouchBar   My good friend wants to kill his MacBook He&amp;rsquo;s already had it, the one in the picture above, for a couple of years, and the battery is starting to degrade. He has a decent budget for a new computer, but doesn&amp;rsquo;t want to buy a new laptop until this one stops functioning.
We are going to destroy the MacBook by heat over the next few weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 15:26:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Sabino Canyon, AZ   Hi! Nice to meet you. My name is Nikolai Nekrutenko and I live in State College, Pennsylvania. I am a rising senior at State College Area High School.
My first language is Russian. This is because my parents come from Kiev, the capital of Ukraine (when they were born it was still part of the Soviet Union). I could not speak any English until I went to daycare.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My First Post</title>
      <link>/posts/my-first-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 15:21:48 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/my-first-post/</guid>
      <description>Hello World!
Why did I make this website and what even is it? I&amp;rsquo;m glad you asked although you probably didn&amp;rsquo;t! I made and will continue to make this website because I want to learn how to build a website. I also enjoy writing, especially when it isn&amp;rsquo;t tied to a grade.
I will be posting about everything from a small cryptocurrency mining operation that I run in the basement to my favorite hobby of RC flight to my own ice cream recipes and everything in between.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>