<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Nikolai Nekrutenko</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Nikolai Nekrutenko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 10:30:15 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>EOLRC - Build Guide</title>
      <link>/posts/eolrc-build-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 10:30:15 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/eolrc-build-guide/</guid>
      <description>Note that this is not a build guide of the car itself. Rather, how to integrate the 3D printed parts with the plane parts for your own projects.
Printing the parts The parts can be found in the plans GitHub repo.
I recommend printing the All_parts_arranged.stl
I used an Ultimaker 3 to print the parts with eSun PLA+ at a 0.2mm layer height at 215C, 35% infill, along with a PETG brim for easy cleanup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Around the Garden</title>
      <link>/gallery/garden/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jul 2020 20:51:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/gallery/garden/</guid>
      <description>I walked around the garden and garage to see what pictures I could make. Here are the ones that I liked:
                                                                                </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vacuum Tube Amplifier</title>
      <link>/gallery/vacuum-tube-amplifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 18:09:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/gallery/vacuum-tube-amplifier/</guid>
      <description>Last night, I was listening to music on a vacuum tube amplifier that I assembled a while back from a kit.
I really liked the look of the tubes in dark, they had a very retro aesthetic. Since they glowed in a very gentle orange-red color, they were perfect for a long exposure.
Maybe it has to do with the look of these tubes, but I&amp;rsquo;m convinced that music sounds better on tubes than on a transistor amp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water Lilies &amp; Dragonflies</title>
      <link>/gallery/waterliliesdragonflies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 16:51:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/gallery/waterliliesdragonflies/</guid>
      <description>Today, I headed down to The Arboretum at Penn State to see what flowers and insects were in store for me.
At first, I decided to bring a 35mm macro lens. However, after seeing all of the dragonflies and lilies, I biked home in record time and snagged a telephoto lens.
I present to you the Water lilies and Dragonflies at The Arboretum at Penn State.
                                                </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EOLRC - An Extremely Overkill LEGO RC Car (from Plane Parts)</title>
      <link>/posts/eolrc-an-extremely-overkill-lego-rc-car-from-plane-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 07:27:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/eolrc-an-extremely-overkill-lego-rc-car-from-plane-parts/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last played around with LEGO Technic. About 4 years to be exact. I can say with absolute confidence that this was my favorite way to spend time in my younger years.
I recollect building all sorts of crazy things from an automatic crossbow to a massive Mercedes Benz Unimog with a functioning suspension and a pneumatic crane. Over the years, I have acquired an impressive amount of LEGO technic parts that are still scattered everywhere around the house.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Book of Bitcoin - An Analogy to Explain Bitcoin</title>
      <link>/posts/the-book-of-bitcoin-an-analogy-to-explain-bitcoin/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 11:48:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/the-book-of-bitcoin-an-analogy-to-explain-bitcoin/</guid>
      <description>This was a project for my speech and debate class, the sources are in the video&amp;rsquo;s description.
Here&amp;rsquo;s the video version of the speech:
  Here&amp;rsquo;s the transcript of the speech:
What do you think of when you hear the word “Bitcoin”? According to a 2017 YouGov survey, 62% of Americans believe that cryptocurrencies, like Bitcoin, are used for illegal purchases or don’t know what they’re used for at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solstice Fun</title>
      <link>/gallery/solstice-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 10:45:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/gallery/solstice-fun/</guid>
      <description>I went camping with my family in the beautiful Northern PA countryside, near the finger lakes.
To celebrate the longest day of the year, I found a stick about my height and lit both ends of it on fire. It was similar to the staff that I use in Tang Soo Do, so I messed around with various techniques. Particularly, I really enjoy doing the figure-eight technique where you essentially spin the stick in the shape of an infinity sign.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nikolai&#39;s Mowing</title>
      <link>/mowing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jun 2020 15:26:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/mowing/</guid>
      <description>Why am I doing this? Strangely enough, I enjoy lawn mowing and find it to be an effective mind relaxant probably because I like enjoying the outdoors.
It&amp;rsquo;s the summer in the middle of the COVID-19 pandemic, and I want to earn some cash that I can use to fuel my hobbies and to start saving for the future.
Business model and info Customer satisfaction is at the core of Nikolai&amp;rsquo;s Mowing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Kill This MacBook! - How to Mine Monero on a Mac</title>
      <link>/posts/lets-kill-this-macbook-how-to-mine-monero-on-a-mac/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jun 2020 10:04:55 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/lets-kill-this-macbook-how-to-mine-monero-on-a-mac/</guid>
      <description>MacBook Pro 13 without TouchBar   My good friend&amp;rsquo;s Mac is nearing its end He&amp;rsquo;s already had it, the one in the picture above, for a couple of years, and the battery is starting to degrade among several other serious issues. Since it is nearing its end soon, in the time that it isn&amp;rsquo;t being used it could mine some cryptocurrency.
MacBooks are known for their subpar cooling systems as demonstrated in this video.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Apr 2020 15:26:54 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>Sabino Canyon, AZ   Hi! Nice to meet you. My name is Nikolai Nekrutenko and I live in State College, Pennsylvania. I am a rising senior at State College Area High School.
I take part in a sport which I have been practicing for over nine years. It is Tang Soo Do, a Korean martial art. I currently hold the rank of black belt candidate.
My favorite hobby is model aviation.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>