<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>RC on Nikolai Nekrutenko</title>
    <link>/tags/rc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in RC on Nikolai Nekrutenko</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 15:12:36 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/rc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Mostly Maine Trip Video</title>
      <link>/posts/the-mostly-maine-trip-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Aug 2020 15:12:36 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/the-mostly-maine-trip-video/</guid>
      <description>Enjoy this video, I&amp;rsquo;m really proud of how it turned out!&#xA;I finally convinced my best friend to lend me his drone after days of trying.&#xA;I actually have a drone, an EMAX Tinyhawk 2, which note to self I still need to fix. I crashed it pretty hard flying on the porch of my house against a metal support beam and one of the ESC&amp;rsquo;s is burned out.&#xA;Enough about my drone.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EOLRC - Build Guide</title>
      <link>/posts/eolrc-build-guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 10:30:15 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/eolrc-build-guide/</guid>
      <description>Note that this is not a build guide of the car itself. Rather, how to integrate the 3D printed parts with the plane parts for your own projects.&#xA;Printing the parts The parts can be found in the plans GitHub repo.&#xA;I recommend printing the All_parts_arranged.stl&#xA;I used an Ultimaker 3 to print the parts with eSun PLA+ at a 0.2mm layer height at 215C, 35% infill, along with a PETG brim for easy cleanup.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>EOLRC - An Extremely Overkill LEGO RC Car (from Plane Parts)</title>
      <link>/posts/eolrc-an-extremely-overkill-lego-rc-car-from-plane-parts/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 07:27:42 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>/posts/eolrc-an-extremely-overkill-lego-rc-car-from-plane-parts/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s been a while since I last played around with LEGO Technic. About 4 years to be exact. I can say with absolute confidence that this was my favorite way to spend time in my younger years.&#xA;I recollect building all sorts of crazy things from an automatic crossbow to a massive Mercedes Benz Unimog with a functioning suspension and a pneumatic crane. Over the years, I have acquired an impressive amount of LEGO technic parts that are still scattered everywhere around the house.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
