<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Galleries on Nikolai Nekrutenko</title>
    <link>/gallery/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Galleries on Nikolai Nekrutenko</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 18:09:23 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/gallery/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Vacuum Tube Amplifier</title>
      <link>/gallery/vacuum-tube-amplifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 18:09:23 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/gallery/vacuum-tube-amplifier/</guid>
      <description>Last night, I was listening to music on a vacuum tube amplifier that I assembled a while back from an electronics kit.
I really liked the look of the tubes in dark, they had a very retro aesthetic. Since they glowed in a very gentle orange-red color, they were perfect for a long exposure.
Maybe it has to do with the look of these tubes, but I&amp;rsquo;m convinced that music sounds better on tubes than on a transistor amp.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Water Lilies &amp; Dragonflies</title>
      <link>/gallery/waterliliesdragonflies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2020 16:51:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/gallery/waterliliesdragonflies/</guid>
      <description>Today, I headed down to The Arboretum at Penn State to see what flowers and insects were in store for me.
At first, I decided to bring a 35mm macro lens. However, after seeing all of the dragonflies and lilies, I biked home in record time and snagged a telephoto lens.
I present to you the Water lilies and Dragonflies at The Arboretum at Penn State.
                                                </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solstice Fun</title>
      <link>/gallery/solstice-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 10:45:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/gallery/solstice-fun/</guid>
      <description>I went camping with my family in the beautiful Northern PA countryside, near the finger lakes.
To celebrate the longest day of the year, I found a stick about my height and lit both ends of it on fire. It was similar to the staff that I use in Tang Soo Do, so I messed around with various techniques. Particularly, I really enjoy doing the figure-eight technique where you essentially spin the stick in the shape of an infinity sign.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>